It's Isaac.
He's here to scare you into watching this dream.
Oh wait, you're already here.
What's going on?
Every time I say what's going on, I really have to suppress the urge to say, from first we feast, my name is Sean Evans.
It is so difficult, but I try to resist it.
What's going on?
Ads?
Oh my god, right now?
You gotta be kidding.
Why didn't I manually roll these during the fucking countdown?
I'm sorry, guys.
I'm gonna write it in chat.
I'm sorry about ads.
I forgot to roll.
I am sorry.
At least it happened now and not when I started playing, huh?
80 seconds.
Welcome to ads.
Today we're doing ads.
Lots of ads.
Binding of ads.
I'll never forgive you, I have turbo.
Well, there you go.
You got turbo.
You're a turbo fowl.
Fowl and basket.
Ugh.
Man, what is it about this stupid game that makes me think about it all the time?
You know what?
I know I'm streaming more often than, you know, last month.
You may think it's because I'm super addicted to Isaac.
And you'd be right.
But it's also because I'm way more healthy now.
I had a shit month last month, okay?
It was not good.
It was a bad spiral.
I'm still on the health train right now and I'm doing great.
And I feel like I have way more energy.
I just want to do more things.
I think it's half and half, you know?
It's half that and half that I'm addicted.
Sure.
I feel fantastic, is all I'm saying.
And I'm also super motivated lately.
I don't know what it is.
Like, I have become turbo addicted to vibe coding in my free time.
I fucking love it!
I have like six agents spun up doing this and that, you know?
One is doing this, another doing that.
It's fucking fun as hell just making stuff.
Without even making stuff.
It's just being made.
I'm pretty much doing that in all my free time.
It is so much fun.
Just making random apps to control random shit in my house or my house in my apartment, I guess, you know?
It is a lot of fun, man.
Anyway, so it's like the perfect flip-flop between Isaac and that, you know?
Reminds me of the time I was living in Germany as a small child.
I think I was maybe 10 years old.
I just remember this golden era.
I had my friend over, you know, and we were playing.
And we would flip-flop between going on the PC and playing Battlefield 1942 until we got Sigurdat.
And then we went to the floor and we played with Legos until we got Sigurdat.
And then as soon as we got Sigurdat, we immediately wanted to play Battlefield again.
So we just flip-flopped between these two states and it was amazing.
And that's pretty much how I'm feeling right now with Isaac and vibe-coding.
It's so dumb, but it's a lot of fun.
Today we got coffee and we got water.
That's the combination.
I just spilled coffee on my hand.
Part of the experience.
Okay, guys, it is time for Isaac to make a comeback.
Today I want to do experimentation.
We're experimenting today.
I will resist the urge to go with Azazel.
We're doing new things today.
It's very difficult, but I will do my best.
Here we go.
I just noticed that I was muted.
I'm sorry, guys.
You missed all my jokes.
I was doing so many jokes.
I apologize.
I also see the chat spamming now.
Okay, calm down.
Calm down.
I made a joke at the start, okay?
I was like, let's do a warm-up with Azazel.
It was funny.
The delivery was on point.
Everything was crisp.
Trust me.
It would have been great if you heard it.
But I was just basically saying that it doesn't seem like there's that many characters.
Because when you look at the circle, it seems massive, right?
But then you skip through and you're already back where you started.
So, I don't know.
I guess we'll try Eulith.
We can't.
It's not unlocked yet.
Neither is Apollyon.
Neither is Bethany.
It's kind of hard to see what's unlocked.
Okay, this one.
I mean, Magdalene or what was the other one?
Eden.
These are unlocked.
This one has a question mark on hearts, speed, and attack.
That is interesting.
I think we should go for it.
Pills.
Oh, that's a wonderful haircut.
Wow.
Oh, we're starting with an item.
Wait, how do I actually... I forgot how to play this game.
Oh yeah, escape.
Crack the sky.
Summon five beams of light from above.
I've seen that before.
Pokey go!
Chance at the start of each new room to summon a permanently charmed monster.
Okay.
Charmed monsters spawned by this item last until they are destroyed by enemy or hazard damage.
Got it.
Gotta collect them all, right?
I know that reference.
Okay.
We're gonna go slow today.
No more bullshit, stupid decisions.
Today, we're really gonna be analyzing every situation, making correct plays, getting a win.
That means using active items.
We're gonna find the tinted rocks.
We're gonna blow them up.
We're gonna create bridges.
That's right.
We're gonna erect monuments and skyscrapers.
And we got spiders.
It's already looking bad.
It's not that bad, actually.
Okay, so I just noticed.
He starts with three HP.
Maybe the HP numbers are randomized on this character every time you play him.
Oh my god, get away from me.
I'm not that fast.
My speed is very pathetic.
Oh, that was close.
We have no bombs, no money, no key.
Okay.
Let me just scan this room with my retina.
Clear.
Nothing in here.
That is suspicious.
We got sloth people.
Oh, he's gonna throw bombs.
No, the little ones are gonna throw bombs.
Ow!
They cannot damage themselves, I imagine.
Oh, there's a little guy.
These guys have so much HP.
There we go.
That's okay so far.
Oh, I forgot to use this.
There we go.
Lay waste to all that oppose you.
I will be using that as soon as possible.
That is a phenomenal chest.
Can I just say that?
That is incredible.
No bombs though, so we cannot access here yet.
Now, I have a theory that these long rooms, the long boys, they are more dangerous than the standard rooms.
So I'm gonna wait with them until I have more upgrades.
This is how crazy I'm optimizing everything right now.
Oh god.
Okay.
Wow.
And again, this room is no joke either.
Not much time to space to maneuver here.
It's looking bad.
Wow.
I'm almost dead.
We gotta find some HP.
Wait, what am I even doing?
This guy needs to die.
And this guy needs to die.
Dude, I cannot hit... Oh, that's lucky.
Very good.
I'm also rich at this point, which is a big deal.
It's nice being rich.
Okay.
Let's go down here.
I'm looking at my active items.
We do not have mana yet.
Oh, there's my Charmed Familiar.
Okay.
Let's have a look around.
Wait, are you gonna be... No.
You're gonna stay Charmed, right?
Why are you making noises?
Oh, we gotta go down here.
See, this is the thing.
I almost went left, but it makes no sense to go here first.
You wanna do the treasure room first.
Mysterious liquid.
Toxic splash damage.
That sounds pretty good.
Cheers.
Tears leave creep where they land.
Creep deals 30 damage per second.
Isn't that kind of crazy?
That is a huge amount of damage.
Considering that my tears do three damage right now.
Wow.
That is unbelievable.
Yeah, look at that creep!
Okay.
Very nice.
This fires evil.
There we go.
I have completely removed the evil.
I really hate evil, guys.
Evil is the worst thing of all time.
So we're not gonna take any trips down evil lane today.
We're not gonna go into those rooms and offer up our hearts.
Unless we have like a million hearts.
Because in my experience, I die when I exchange hearts for items.
It's a bad idea.
Okay.
That is a red spider.
I feel like this creep is not doing much damage.
That was bad.
That's a bomb.
In fact, this whole room is bombs.
Oh, you know what?
I should be playing smart here.
Come to me.
We're gonna blow him up up here.
Ow, ow, ow.
Okay, well...
I thought he was up north.
It's okay.
At least I'm using my items, right?
Okay, now it's time for money.
Very good.
Oh, I forgot to note down how much money was in the donation machine.
Remember I blew that up?
And I was thinking, oh no, did I just reduce the count?
I think I may have reduced the count.
I feel like it was higher than 129.
Uh, playing card, heart, or...
Wait, what's this?
Piggy bank.
My life savings?
How much is in there?
Plus three coins.
Sponsored one to two coins when taking damage.
Ooh, okay.
Now, as part of playing safe...
I'm gonna pick up this heart.
Yeah.
We're not gonna take chances.
Resources are there to be used, right?
Everyone dies.
You see that?
Feeling lucky as well?
Fantastic.
Now, I could go for the boss.
I guess it's the only way.
Yeah.
It's fine.
We're chilling.
Oh, wait, that's a friend.
Help me out, friend.
Damn.
Okay, time for the foreskin.
Man, that one is really tough to dodge.
Whoo, I did it.
Am I crazy, or is he shooting with a higher frequency than normal?
This is a harder version of this boss.
Okay, now he's gonna shoot again.
We're gonna hide.
Come on, do your thing.
Oh, maybe it is random.
Okay, never mind.
Nice, that was super good.
I have terrible aim, though.
Nice, clean.
Very clean.
We got a pentagram.
Pentagram, more damage increases devil angel room chance.
We're gonna go for angel rooms.
Actually, we could go for both.
Why wouldn't you do both?
I mean, if you have enough HP, right?
I guess it depends on that.
I am actually gonna try and find more stuff in here.
I'm gonna go through this room over here and take some damage.
Man, I really want to get in here, but I can't.
No bombs.
He's invisible?
Beautiful.
Man, this room was totally worth.
Totally worth.
Oh, nice.
I'm gonna blow this up.
Okay, very good.
And that was the first floor.
I think that went pretty well.
Not bad.
Cheers for that.
Okay.
Man, we were just bald.
Did you see that?
Before anything else.
Oh, he's my friend.
This is a new one.
Part HP up.
Straight up, huh?
Okay.
Very nice.
Let's go up.
Yeah, look at me go.
I'm pressing buttons, guys.
Oh, wait, that's a friend.
Oh, here we go.
Yeah.
Oh, what a chest.
Wow.
We got four... Oh, do I go in there, though?
No.
I hate that.
That room has always been bad for me.
But we are gonna have to experiment with it more, though.
Oh, my God.
Look at this one, too.
Does it get more obvious?
Oh, wait, that's a friend.
Okay.
Finally!
Oh, God.
Oh, we got bombs down there.
Check this out.
Sweet, ain't it?
Oh, he died in the creep.
Nice.
Come here.
Scanning the room.
Clean.
Everything looks good to me.
I could go in here, but let's wait.
Maybe we find a card that teleports us.
The ultimate plays are being made right now.
Okay.
You need to...
He's standing in the creep.
Why was he not taking damage?
Oh, there we go.
Money.
I'm doing really well on money.
I'd love to find another store.
Okay, can't get to those poops.
This is... Yeah, here's the store!
A cake?
Or a battery or something.
Magic fingers.
Pay to win?
Why is that called magic fingers?
Consumes one coin to damage all enemies in the room.
Damage scales with tier damage.
I want to find more damage then.
Ah, but wait, I think I may like this more.
Yeah.
I'm going to donate.
There we go.
131.
Don't forget.
Got mini I6.
I think the creep is actually helping so much.
It is doing damage.
A good amount of it too.
Okay.
Uh oh.
Wow, that was lucky.
How did I dodge that?
That felt really lucky.
Anything suspicious in here?
Not really.
Ooh, I can definitely do a double wombo here.
Nice, nice.
Okay.
I mean, we may as well just do the boss, I guess.
Yeah, just do the boss.
Pin.
The guy that jumps.
Oh, he also has this little guy.
Yeah, stay in the creep.
That makes me happy.
Very good.
That was clean.
Straight up clean.
We got breakfast out of it.
Ooh, look at all the hearts we have.
Now's the time to do this.
What is that?
The mark.
Speed, damage, black heart.
Yeah, why not?
I'll gladly change or exchange your heart for that.
Very good.
Okay, now we go back because there's still more stuff to do.
I'm looking for the tinted rocks.
I don't see any.
Uh-oh.
Wait, what's the point of this room?
Do I really want to blow it up to get a bomb back?
Wait, maybe there is a secret here because this room is suspicious as hell?
Oh, my God, I'm on a roll.
I'm on a roll.
You were born wrong.
No.
I was born right.
We got the fool.
You know what that means.
You know what that actually...
Let's try and blow this.
Oh, we can't blow it up though.
You will die alone.
Most likely.
What do you want to do today?
Play Isaac.
Only a sinner.
That's wrong.
I'm a winner.
Short fuse.
Isaac's bombs detonate faster.
They deal more damage.
That's going to replace my...
Uh-huh, okay.
What was the horseshoe thing?
15% chance for the treasure room to contain two items.
No, no, I want this instead.
For sure.
Absolutely.
Okay.
Now we're going to use the card.
Uh-oh.
Well, that's unfortunate.
Nice.
Wait, what is happening?
Oh, I have...
My heart is beating outside of my chest.
It doesn't look like a heart.
It looks like something else.
Yeah.
It looks weird.
All right, we're moving on.
Ooh.
Very nice.
Next floor.
I'm telling you, precision gaming today.
No mistakes.
Sharp as an arrow.
We're not going to mind the clouds.
Fuck them.
We're not going to rule how we are.
How we feel.
Uh-oh.
These ones are dangerous as hell.
I'm being cornered.
I couldn't do anything.
I'm cornered.
It's over.
I mean, it's not over, but I'm going to take damage.
I could...
No, that's not worth it.
Let's go...
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I see it.
Mr. Mega has appeared.
Yoink!
Ha ha ha!
Okay, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I don't have a bomb, but if I had a bomb, I could make a bridge here.
But I don't have a bomb.
So, rest in peace.
Give me that.
Oh, we can refresh?
This looks like milk, though.
I like it.
Almond milk.
Damage down?
Oh, no.
Oh, what the fuck?
That sounds horrible.
Okay, we gain more tiers.
That's attack speed, right?
Greatly increases fire rate and greatly decreases tier damage.
Each tier gains a random worm effect that alters its trajectory.
What?
I don't know about that, bro.
That seems a little not good.
This may have been a mistake.
We're gonna have to see.
Oh, I mean, it's not... that bad?
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
Kill him.
Okay, I mean, I'm definitely doing a lot less damage.
A lot less.
Super battery?
Or a tarot card?
I'm gonna save up.
Okay, watch this.
Wait.
Here.
Yeah!
So good.
Oh, god.
Wow.
What could be dodging today?
I never dodged this well.
I'm a changed man.
Oh, wow.
Moving on.
Let's go right.
Boom.
Wait, they're still enemies?
Oh, I thought he was my friend.
So confused.
Please just die, will you?
Man, I'm not doing a lot of damage.
I need more damage.
Is it worth it?
Do I exchange some HP here?
I don't know.
I don't think so.
Spawn six troll bombs.
Okay.
Why not?
Oh, god!
Wait, you can push bombs?
What was that just now?
Duct tape.
I thought it was toilet paper.
Familias will stick in their relative positions to Isaac.
Ooh!
That could be pretty good, actually, if you have a lot of familiars.
Uh, wait.
This way.
Man, this guy's butt is so, I don't know, naked, you know?
Kinda nuts.
Kill all the dangerous ones first.
Nice.
My shots are a little bit homing, which is nice.
Oh, thank you, Familiar!
Petrified poop?
50% chance for destroyed poops to spawn a pickup.
Dude, I like that even more than the horseshoe.
That sounds really good.
There's a lot of poop in this game.
Okay.
Man, this Familiar is incredible.
Or my little charmed helper.
Oh, he's gone now, unfortunately.
He got destroyed.
Man, I do almost no damage here.
And they're not touching the creep because they're flying.
Oh, that's an enemy.
Okay.
Can we find some poop?
Should I go in this room down here?
Uh...
Yeah.
Let's do it.
No, I don't have a bomb!
Oh, that's rough.
Whoops.
Well, okay.
Time to go, uh, to the boss.
Wait, I have money.
Maybe I can buy a bomb?
No.
But with all this money, I may actually purchase something.
The devil!
Revel in the power of darkness.
Question mark!
We don't even know what it is!
I'm assuming it's good, so let's use it in here.
Uh, let's go.
Revel in the power.
I have devil horns.
Am I just doing more damage or something?
Oh my god.
What's happening?
This is freaking chaos!
Wow, that did absolutely nothing.
Useless.
I almost died.
This room was insanity.
Oui, oui, oui.
Okay, we got some HP back, though.
That's good.
Alright, uh, I'll be done here.
I think we're done here.
Moving on.
Not too bad!
Crushed my toys.
My favorite toys.
Ooh, that's nice.
Aries, more speed.
When moving fast enough, running into enemies will deal contact damage to the enemy.
Oh, that one, I feel like it's too risky.
Like, I don't want to try and rely on that, you know?
Like, when am I max speed?
It's hard to tell.
I don't know.
What is this room?
Nothing in there.
Come on, random bullets, go!
Okay.
Not bad.
Uh, let's not go in there just yet.
In case we find a teleport card.
Oh my god, kill him.
I do little damage here, man.
But the fact that I'm so fast is helping me a lot.
And where's all the poop when you need it?
Nice, we got a familiar.
Wait, something happened?
We got a pop-up for something?
I didn't pay attention.
Oh, wow.
What is this familiar even doing?
It's not helping me.
There you are.
Checking the rocks.
Nothing suspicious here.
Yeah, everything looks good.
Okay, moving on.
Oh my god.
As soon as they peep, peep.
Here we go.
Oh my god!
Got in the corner.
Ooh, I gotta find some damage, or I think it's pretty much over.
Best familiar ever.
I mean, I guess I'm getting money every time I take damage.
It was actually part of my strategy.
Oh god.
Uh, oh, the button, I see.
Oh, there's another one.
Oh man, this familiar is so good!
Looking for secrets.
I don't see any.
Evil fires.
Nice.
Oh, there's another one!
I thought I cleared the room.
Whoops.
Uh, nothing suspicious in here either.
We got money.
We can buy this, uh, backpack?
More trinket room.
Faded pull-up.
Wait, what?
Where did that come from?
Spawned with this one, I guess?
Allows two trinkets to be held at a time.
Trinket is the one in the bottom left, right?
Spawns one random trinket on pickup.
Okay, so that is a trinket.
Faded Polaroid.
Isaac gains camouflage for a few seconds at random intervals.
Enemies are confused while camouflage is active.
Can be used to open a strange door!
Oh?
You feel faded.
Wait, where is it?
Oh wait, it's in the bottom!
Very left.
Wait, I've never seen that!
So, this is the first time I've ever had a trinket, I guess.
Okay.
Interesting.
Uh, I'll buy this.
Destroy these fires.
I'll take this one too.
Donate my money.
Nah, not yet.
This guy is so valuable to have with me.
I'm gonna time it so that he's gonna shoot right when we enter.
Is that optimization or what?
Now, what door are we talking about here though?
This is very intriguing.
Man!
How tough is this?
Oh, special key!
Well, now we can open any door.
We can open all doors and strange doors.
Whatever those are.
Uh, I could go to the arcade.
Oh, aha!
He was gonna surprise me while I was gambling, huh?
Not falling for that.
Come on now.
Mom's pearl.
Ten percent increased chance of finding soul hearts, black hearts, and bone hearts.
Oh, wait, wait, wait!
I see now!
So, the bottom left...
Okay, the BLI is the trinket.
Well, you can switch between them.
Wait, someone told me last time how to do it.
I forgot the keybind.
Uh, it was not control.
Alright.
Maybe it was the bottom right one you switched out.
Wait, so now I have... oh yeah, now I have these two.
Now I have this one and the poop.
Which one do I want more?
Oh, wait, I can check it out like this.
Okay, well...
bombs for me!
I wanna open strange doors.
Evil tomatoes, gotta go!
Oh, wow.
Any suspicious Rockies?
Doesn't look like it.
Arcade time.
The Game Kid has appeared in the basement!
Ooh.
Bombs, hearts, and you want coins.
I'll give you coins.
Why not?
Uh-oh.
Well, okay, another special key!
We are opening all the doors.
Uh, six bombs?
I'd rather save these bombs, honestly.
I like having bombs.
In fact, let's go look for some secret areas.
I could be one here.
Shit!
What is the most secret place you could put a secret room?
I'll do two more bombs.
I think in this big room, there's gotta be something.
It's not this one, because I already checked the top one.
Maybe we put... this could be anywhere.
Let's not check this room, this is a bad idea.
Let's try... This one seems like a secret, doesn't it?
Oi!
I'm so good at this game.
Thanks, bombs for me.
Wait, when I'm camouflaged, does that mean the enemies cannot even see me, or what?
It seems crazy.
Let me blow you up.
We gained five in the demon meter.
Oi!
We even unlocked this?
Huh.
Okay, let me, uh...
blow you up.
Not that money is the most important thing right now, you know, still.
Okay, I think we're good.
We can leave.
Or fight the boss, I mean.
Up here...
Man, I really wanna blow up these rocks, even though they don't look tinted to me.
I feel like there's just so many, maybe something happens.
Let's do it.
Okay, nothing happened.
It's time for Pete.
He's shooting green stuff?
I'm shooting green stuff.
Aw, man.
It's not going well.
Oh, yeah!
I can hit every time!
The projectiles are just too fast for me.
Okay, there we go.
Maybe the trick is to go at range when he comes down.
Gimme that.
We got him.
That was a close one.
That's a tough boss.
Uh, torn photo.
Oh, that's good!
No!
Wait, tears?
Shot speed.
That's even more attack speed.
Oh!
Minigun.
Okay.
There is still a room we missed, actually, in the bottom right.
And maybe we can check whether or not that special room is open now.
Uh, the fight room.
Mini boss, champion room.
I think it was... Yeah, it's closed.
Why is that?
This is still a massive mystery to me.
So there's a skull on it, and two swords.
Sometimes you find these rooms without the skull on it, and there's swords on it.
And that's like a small challenge room, right?
But when the skull is on it, it's like bosses are in there.
Mini versions of bosses.
But the way to open them...
I think it's somehow related to the demon meter.
Because notice we're at 0% right now.
Maybe you need to cross a certain threshold to have those open for you.
I'm gonna go in here.
The lovers!
May you prosper and something else.
Want's two red hearts!
Okay, we're gonna save that.
Actually, we can use it now.
Hey!
Isn't it amazing how everything just works out?
Now I wonder if I go inside the dice room.
If that door will unlock.
Maybe it is related to all the rooms being explored, you know?
I'm gonna try, I have so many keys, so who cares?
Oh wait, my keys are not being consumed when I open doors!
That's what that means!
Two-sided...
Okay, let's try this.
I will pay attention to what I have.
Hokey-go, liquid, piggy bank, pentagram.
Heart, crackers, berries, meat, almond milk, mark, breakfast torn photo.
If I see something new now, I will notice.
Also, look at my stats when I do it.
Okay.
Aha!
Nothing changed!
So wait, what did happen?
Okay, check this out, guys.
You see the room we couldn't enter in the top right?
Ah, we're gonna try two things.
First, we're gonna go back and see if it's open now.
And if it's not, I'm gonna go back to the dice room.
Okay, it's closed.
Watch this now.
We're gonna make our way in there some other way.
Through here.
Fuck!
Oh, okay.
Wait, there's money in those jars?
Huh!
Okay.
Nevermind.
Alright, let's go.
Moving on.
Although, I kind of want to bomb here.
What if we bomb right after the boss?
That's exciting, isn't it?
Okay, well, this is the...
You know, this is the day of experimentation.
We're gonna try all kinds of things.
Depths one.
Full HP.
Massive attack speed.
Barely any damage.
Let's do this.
Oh, I've got a poopy bot as well.
Give them some of their own medicine.
Yeah, the big rooms are always more difficult, I think.
Ooh.
Man, my familiar is good.
Incredible.
Infinite range as well.
I mean, popping off.
As long as I protect this guy, we should be able to be a crazy combo.
Friends forever.
So we're gonna time it.
Ah, I messed it up.
We're gonna protect them.
Okay, he's still alive.
Survive.
So far so good.
Let's go back this way.
Whoa, what a room.
Holy cannoli.
Look at all that stuff.
Uh, wait, is there a way to get in there?
Let me think.
Yeah, there is...
There is right here.
But I have no bombs.
I've got no bombs, so whatever.
Doesn't matter.
But I have to kill these, right?
How do I... wait, how do I actually leave?
Oh, I can leave now.
What?
Maybe the game realized that I couldn't actually do anything, so it just opened the doors for me?
Is that what happened?
Oh my god, I do no damage at all!
Things just won't die.
I shouldn't have picked that item up.
That gave me attack speed.
I think it was a mistake.
But it will not have been a mistake if we find a lot of damage later.
And it's gonna be really good.
Uh, what is this thing?
It's the thing you used to garden with, right?
Oh, it's a potato peeler.
A pound of flesh.
Consumes one red heart container to grant a permanent cube of meat familiar and a permanent damage up.
Activation also grants the anemic effect for the current room.
Wait, consumes one red heart... Oh, it's an active!
Consumes one red heart container.
Permanent cube of meat.
Uh, that was very little extra damage we got there.
That was horrible.
That is absolutely terrible.
Unless it's randomized.
I'm not gonna try again.
That's horrible.
I'll take a pill, though.
Speed down!
It's going horribly.
Uh, how do I salvage this shit?
Uh, okay, let's just move on for now.
Maybe I'll come back for that one if I find more HP.
Um,
go!
That was a bit risky.
Come on, familiar.
Shoot him!
Where is he going?
Boss is here.
Not yet.
Get blown up!
I think, uh, this active I have now is better against enemies that stand still.
Or, or immobilize.
I have two with me now!
Two friends!
Whoa!
I'm gonna amass an army.
Uh, here.
Wait, let me wait until I get camouflaged.
Then I enter.
Wait, how does it work?
I need to read that again.
Which one was it?
Oh, it's a faded Polaroid.
Isaac gains camouflage for a few seconds at random intervals.
Okay, it's just random.
They're confused while camouflage is active.
Can be used to open a strange door!
Wait a minute, faded Polaroid?
There's three people in that image.
Are we getting some lore here about Isaac?
Is that his dad and his mom?
Because where?
Oh, speaking of mom!
We got mom here!
Oh, I ran into that like an idiot.
That was bad.
Okay.
Is she still here?
Nope, I think we're good.
Oh, all this evil fire needs to die right now.
Oi, oi, oi.
I think the purple one is evil too.
We're not gonna risk it.
Turns it blue!
Cool.
Not gonna enter there.
My damage is so pathetic.
I got three bombs.
I thought I accidentally would've...
Ooh, no, no, no, no, no, wait, this is gonna damage me.
That's fine, I guess.
Dimballed, but grants an increase to all stats when health, active.
Items charged is fully depleted.
Oh, wait, this is another trinket.
Do we want that instead of the ball?
Yeah, fuck the ball.
We don't care about that.
I like this.
We're gonna try it, see how it feels.
There's also a big room we didn't explore yet.
And I have my light from the sky ready, in case we need it.
Why is nothing in here?
What is this room?
Oh, these guys are so hard.
Thank you, familiar.
I appreciate it.
I think we're good.
Wow, wow, wow, wow, wow, wow, wow.
I'm in the corner.
Dude, I'm tickling the enemies.
I'm literally doing nothing to them.
Wow.
Imagine finding some damage.
Like, any little damage I find, it's gonna matter so much because of the shot speed.
Explosivo.
What was this?
To fire a sticky tear that will grow and explode?
Oh, right.
I mean, that was very good last time I had it because I also got healed from bombs.
But with this attack speed, I mean, chances of putting bombs on enemies is gonna be huge, you know?
Yeah, and we can't enter here.
Look, two swords.
There's not a skull on it.
And the icon is a blue sword.
It's a fight room.
Um, four bombs.
I mean, this map is so big, there's no chance I'm gonna find the secret room just accidentally.
I really wanna find more of those items that give me the sight to see the secrets.
Had so much of that at one point, and then I never saw it again.
It was a lot of fun.
Let's go to the boss.
I like it.
Also, this cube of meat that's around me right now.
Can I see that here?
It's the gate.
The gatekeeper himself.
Spawn those bombs on him, come on.
Wow!
Okay, oh, oh, oh, we're not done, we're not done.
There we go.
Blood clod.
Plus one damage in range!
Huge!
That's massive!
We like that.
Uh, with full HP, I think I'm actually gonna go to that room now.
Yeah, I shouldn't have picked up both hearts, that was a mistake there.
It happens.
Now we go this way.
And here.
Ooh!
Curse of the tower, embrace chaos!
Oh, oh, what, buh buh buh!
Fook, okay.
What did I just get?
Spawn six troll bombs in random locations around the room each time.
Isaac takes damage!
Uh oh.
Does not trigger from demon beggars or block donation machines.
I really need to get healed from bombs now.
I really need to get healed, man.
This is gonna be...
kind of bad with explosivo and everything else going on.
What I'm saying is...
I need to pay more attention to what's happening on the screen than ever before.
Wish me luck.
I'll need it!
This is the mom run.
Let's remember, it's mom time.
Okay, small rooms first.
Absolutely.
Wow.
Yeah, you're gonna blow up, son.
Wonderful.
We're gonna make liberal use of this.
Nice.
Wait, mine is all my stats!
You saw it?
Unless I gain the buff by entering.
And then I lost it now.
Wait, what is happening here?
Why did I just lose all those stats?
Not that one.
Increases devil, angel, room, chance.
Oh, wait, wait, so...
There's a hundred percent on demon... or...
What do you call it?
Devil now?
So that means there's a hundred percent chance I'm gonna get a devil room.
Where I can offer up hearts.
And it's only after the boss.
But I still don't understand why I lost all my stats.
Just now.
That is such a mystery.
Okay.
Uh-oh.
Holy shit!
Wow!
This is gonna kill me, guys.
I will die to those bombs.
Pretty fly.
Right, we get a fly around us.
Oh, no.
Kill these hearts!
The bombs are gonna help me here.
Okay, he's not dead yet.
Wow.
There we go.
Man, that is indeed chaos.
Kill them all.
Played safe.
Uh-oh, bombs, bombs.
Wow!
There you go, son.
Oh, no.
He has bombs on him.
Wonderful.
Okay.
Uh, I have a feeling, guys.
Ah!
Man, imagine though.
Imagine.
We're gonna spawn a bunch of bombs.
And we're gonna peace out.
Enjoy!
Uh, man.
Okay, the boss is here.
I need to get some HP first, though.
We can't fight mom with two hearts.
Oh, shit!
Oh, my god!
Man, oh, man.
I'm in deep trouble.
Oh, no, not this sort of thing.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Guys, I think it's over.
The bombs are just too much for me.
Kill them!
Good, good!
Oh, man.
I'm camouflaged.
They are mega confused.
Blow up!
Rain shot?
No!
That's bad.
Oh, not spiders!
It's over!
Maybe.
Oh, somehow it's not.
We got a heart.
Huge.
Whoa!
Kill him!
Somehow, I'm surviving.
I don't know how.
What is that now?
Mom's eyeshadow.
Chance to fire charming tears.
Chance increases with luck.
I mean, with a lot of attack speeds.
Could be good.
Yeah!
That's how we do that.
Blow that up.
No hearts for me.
Let's look for secrets.
Shit.
Wait, where is this room?
Chest room!
Oh!
Secret here, for sure.
No!
Okay, fine.
This way.
Whoa!
Oh, man.
Oh, man, oh, man.
Okay!
Open up!
The Emperor, teleport to the boss room.
I mean, okay, I'm not going to go in there.
No way.
Come on now.
Horrible idea.
Well, I think it's time for the boss.
No, wait, there's another room I missed.
Down here.
Oh, wow.
Man, no healing.
Blow up here.
Come on!
Show me the secrets.
One bomb left.
I want to use it somewhere before we move to the boss.
Oh, dude!
We're going to get HP.
Didn't even see this thing.
Man, come on now.
Again, finding bombs is not too bad either.
I mean, I am so rich.
I can gamble forever.
Almost.
That was too hard.
No!
It blew up.
It was too much gambling.
It couldn't handle it.
Wait, wait, wait.
There's an axe on the floor.
What?
Okay, look at the way this is aligned here.
Jesus Christ, I'm bad at this.
Definitely in here, though.
Oh, no!
Not this room!
Fast!
Okay, we're fine, we're fine.
I made it through somehow.
Well, we're about to fight Mom with one HP.
And if we take damage, there's bombs all over the place.
It is pretty much over, I think.
Phew!
Wish me luck.
Shit!
Yeah, I was looking for the shadow.
I'm too slow.
That was it.
What a fantastic warm-up run.
I like this character.
Oh, look at this!
It is indeed randomized.
We got tiny heads on our head.
And we have TNT?
Minecrafter?
Spawns a pushable TNT barrel.
Using the item again detonates the barrel.
Giant cell.
Taking damage spawns a mini familiar that chases and attacks enemies.
These mini familiars last until destroyed from taking enough damage.
Max of 16.
Okay.
We also have one red heart and two blue hearts.
So, let me check this now.
We're gonna do this.
Oh, I see.
I thought it would be like the ice, you know, where it just flies toward a wall.
Whoa!
Matchstick!
Tastes like burning.
What did that do again?
Increase chance of finding bombs as room clear rewards.
Add an additional bomb to chests.
Tinted rocks and destroyed machines.
Do I want bombs that bad, though, is the question.
I guess it's fine.
Phone book.
Telepathy for dummies.
Temporary psychic shit.
Gain nothing.
Gain homing tiers and increased range for the current room.
So, it replaces TNT.
Homing shots and increased range.
Honestly, I don't want that to become a crutch.
I'm using this.
No, I'm gonna use it in this room and then we're moving on.
May as well use the mana, right?
Okay, there we go.
It is indeed homing.
Now I grab the other thing again.
Oh, here we go!
Yeah!
Very nice.
Poop me.
I wonder if I should wait with the poop.
Let's say I find the item that gives a chance to find more stuff in poop, you know.
Then I'll have poop left over.
Actually, that's probably a good idea.
But, I mean, gambling on that is still a little risky.
Man, I'm getting rich!
Money is not a problem today, it seems.
Ah, not the key thing, I hate that.
I could reroll.
I think it's five coins to reroll.
But I do like my pills.
Okay, that's fine, I guess.
I could come back and reroll later.
Kill the little guys.
Okay.
Hey, we're getting lots of resources.
It's a great start.
I'm channeling them into this choke point.
You know what, why not?
We're gonna blow them up with this.
Fuck!
Walk to me.
Oh, it's actually kinda good!
That was a lot of damage.
Very nice.
Oh, he's so mad.
Wonderful.
Caffeine pill!
More speed, decreases the size.
And a random pill.
Oh my god, that's amazing!
Good stuff.
Ah, I'm not gonna go into that room down there.
I hate that room.
With the spikes on the floor.
It's horrible.
Cheers.
Speaking of caffeine, I'm gonna sip my last coffee here.
Ah, nice.
Ah, you gotta be kidding me.
That was very unnecessary.
I'm gonna save this poop for later.
We'll save it for the feast.
Galatney, this is gonna make lasers.
Or not.
Yeah, yeah, he's... Oh, look at that butt.
Man, come on.
Okay, not too bad.
Lots of bombs.
Well, in that case...
Man, I'm getting unlucky with this.
Whoa!
Now, this...
How do I do that?
I could enter here.
I also have my active.
Hmm...
Sure.
Nice.
I think it's worth.
Oh my... Yeah, we got bombs back!
Amazing.
It paid off.
Oh, no.
I am lacking HP, though.
This is kind of a problem.
The jar.
Save your life.
Spawn red heart pickups stored in the jar.
Collect red hearts while at full health to store them in the jar.
Up to four hearts can be stored at once.
That sounds pretty good.
But, man, I do like the TNT.
It's kind of good, as well.
But since we're low on hearts here, I think it makes sense.
Come on, then.
Oh, the little guy is... How did I get that guy?
Was that the giant cell?
Yeah, mini familiars.
I'm gonna leave the poop.
Man, it requires so much effort for me to dodge those shots.
These guys don't shoot any projectiles, I think.
I want that pill.
That doesn't sound good.
Paralysis?
Uh-oh.
Hippocampus?
Politactily.
Hold me.
Say what?
Allows holding two cards, pills, or runes at a time.
Drops one random card, pill or rune on pickup.
I can just pick it up again, though.
May I never miss your goal?
That was...
range, okay.
Okay, here we go, here we go.
Fuck!
Man, I'm bad at that today.
Well, I say that, and it's really just gamblings.
You can't really be good at it.
I've been very unlucky, is what I'm saying.
Nice!
That was good.
The moon.
Oh, secret room!
I love that.
We got poop!
Hell yeah.
Thanks, brothers.
For that, I'm gonna blow you up.
Nice!
I was hoping to hit the last one as well, but I lost.
It shall not be the case.
Oh, I blasted here when I could have blasted there.
Unfortunate.
Um...
Blow it up.
Amazing.
Is it storing?
Half a heart right now, or what?
Yeah!
Fuck!
I hate getting caught in a corner!
I keep thinking my guys are enemies.
Yeah, I'm storing hearts.
It's great.
Boss time?
Yeah, I think so.
Gurglings.
Now I just have to remember, when I'm low HP, I gotta use my active, because it's a heal.
Nice.
More damage?
More range?
Boss on this item apply only to shots fired from the right eye.
Okay, that's fine.
Oh, here we go.
Ah, that's gonna kill me, though!
If I pick these two up...
And I then take it now.
I'm gonna... Wait, it says one heart extra now, there.
I'm gonna try it.
We didn't die!
Oh, okay.
That was fucking close.
Lord of the pit!
Grant's flight!
No way!
Upside down cross.
More speed.
Oh my gosh!
Okay, I think that was worth it, even though we only have one heart.
Where can we fly now?
Oh my goodness.
I don't know.
Wait, there's a pill in here?
Oh, there is!
Lockup!
Awesome!
Okay.
Yeah!
Hey, dude, this is awesome.
Um, what do I grab here?
I can refresh.
Dreamcatcher.
And a card.
Why isn't it showing?
Oh, it is.
Okay.
I'm gonna buy it.
Sweet Dreams.
Alters the dream sequences between floors to instead preview the next treasure room item and boss.
Wait, what?
Alters the dream sequences?
Dream sequences?
Oh, the ones where I dream about the clouds giving me the finger.
I see.
Oh, that's cool.
Grant plus one soul heart at the start of each new floor.
Oh!
That's actually pretty cool.
I still can't believe we're flying.
That's the first time I've gained this ability on a character other than a Seizel.
Like, I think I've gotten flying like two or three times before, but it was always on a Seizel when I already could fly.
So not really helpful there.
Okay.
Let's go to the next level.
Or we start to blow up stuff here.
I like that, actually.
Very unlucky with that.
Okay, we find a bomb and we're gonna fight...
I don't know who that is.
Dude, that's so cool, so they're gonna have actual cinematics for all of those combinations?
What?
That's crazy.
Oh my god, oh my god.
Wait, you can't get to me, noobs!
I can fly, bitch!
Trying to avoid playing a Seizel and I somehow end up playing a Seizel anyway.
It's great.
These guys are very slow.
Good.
A long room is scary.
Let's go this way.
Oh, fuck this!
I'm actually dead.
Bro, I can't...
These enemies are the worst in the game, it's over, it's over!
I can't win against this.
I can't.
This room is a fucking killer.
Every time I'm in this room, I die, it's just impossible.
Those enemies are off the wall difficult.
It's crazy.
What is this?
Breath of Life.
Holding Use depletes the charge bar.
Isaac becomes invincible when the charge bar is empty.
Touching enemies while invincible summons light beams.
Touching an enemy at the same time the charge bar is empty fires a four-way beam.
That's way too much for my brain, bro.
Holding Use depletes the charge bar.
Okay.
That is so confusing.
Almond Milk.
More tears, less damage.
Dude, now I have no damage.
Again.
Greatly increases fire... Oh, again?
I don't like this item!
I hate it!
So I'm in... I'm in... I thought I was invisible!
Oh, I need to hold... Oh, I see.
Huh?
Did I take damage from the black stuff?
I am so confused.
Holding it depletes the charge bar.
It becomes invincible.
Touching enemies...
Okay.
Wait, there's more?
Holding Use after the charge bar is empty causes continual damage to Isaac.
What the... This is the worst item I've ever had.
I hate having to keep track of all that.
That's way too much for my brain.
Okay.
I thought I was invincible, but okay.
I was holding the button.
Sure.
That is annoying.
Nice haircut, bro!
Is that a skirt?
What is going on here?
I like this look.
Crack the sky...
and Guppy's tail.
Increases chance of chests as room clear rewards.
Okay.
That sounds horrible because it also decreases chances for anything to happen at all.
Ah, I've only had to destroy this one, huh?
That would have been perfect.
Come here.
Nice!
More money.
Okay.
Ah, pulse pickup items toward Isaac.
I've had this before.
Okay.
Very nice.
At least we're gonna be able to collect items.
Yeah, like this.
Yeah.
Uh-oh.
These fires are gonna shoot me.
Oh, yeah!
A good pill.
Very good.
I'm playing it very carefully here.
I also like that we have three normal hearts.
I hate the random heart shit.
Red hearts all the way.
Red heart supremacy.
All those other types of hearts, I hate them.
Okay.
Get blasted, nerds.
Look at the coins just approaching me.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
We can go.
Oh, no, I have no bombs.
Damn.
Maybe we can buy some.
There's a shop here and I have a lot of money.
Seems like an idea.
Dream catch.
I don't like that very much, actually.
No.
We got a bomb, though.
I'm excited.
Okay.
Moving faster.
Sounds like a temporary effect.
Now we can destroy this tinted rock.
And hopefully we get more bombs, honestly.
And keys.
Bombs and keys.
Okay, I'll take those.
Widow.
This guy used to be tough, but I think he's okay now.
It's not too bad.
Fuck.
Wait, why am I fast?
Never mind, I'm still bad at this.
Wait, everything is fast.
It's not just me, it's also the boss.
Bro, what the hell?
Wow.
He's way too fast.
Why are things moving so fast?
What is going on?
There's nothing here about that.
Glass eye.
Okay.
That sounds pretty good, at least.
Why are things moving fast?
Like, I took a speed pill before, but that effect was done!
So what the fuck is going on?
Is it just back randomly or what?
They gifted me poop in a box.
So all of those are dreams, huh?
Look at them moving in a pack.
Are they avoiding my shots?
It feels like it.
I don't think they are, but it feels like it.
No bombs.
We obviously go here.
A remote control?
Teleport.
Teleport Isaac to another room.
Uh...
Sure.
Oh my god.
There we go.
Okay, got some healing there.
That's big.
I'm just going to teleport every time I can.
Maybe we end up in this secret room, right?
That would be nice.
At least I don't have that stupid item that makes my damage small again.
And attack speed higher.
That is honestly one of the worst items.
Okay.
Nothing suspicious in here.
I am amassing a little bit of money.
So perhaps we do hit the arcade after this.
Look at the keys coming towards me.
Amazing.
Ah, I could get in there.
I have keys.
Let's do it.
Oh, that was a delicious chest.
Can't ask for much more than that.
And a stapler.
More damage.
Hell yeah.
Now it's only the right eye that shoots.
That mechanic is still a bit weird to me.
We didn't get to end up in the secret room, unfortunately.
Oh yeah, the damage is good now.
Feels nice.
Oh, I don't have a key anymore.
Ooh, no.
Okay.
No, I really want a key.
Let's hit the arcade and see if we can get some keys out of that.
I gotta do it.
Gambling.
I actually kind of like the drip here.
Look at this, the haircut.
The magnet is kind of vibing with the bloodshot eye and everything.
This is a real vibe right here.
Lovely.
Uh, okay.
Who do I give money to?
Both.
High roller.
Stay asleep.
Wait, it changed my mana bar to be yellow.
I'm not sure what that means.
Come on, man, give me something good.
Oh, wait!
You always give me that.
Okay, I see.
Follow the dog.
What dog?
Your soul is hidden deep within the darkness.
Follow the dog.
A key.
10% increased chance of finding keys.
Oh, I like that.
We are very low on them.
And then some chance to add an additional key to chests, tinted rocks, and destroyed machines.
So that means we're gonna destroy this now.
And we're gonna find a key.
Hey!
And this one as well.
And this guy.
We're using all the bombs.
Fuck it.
Suck on that.
Wonderful.
Okay.
Very nice.
Let me use this.
Ah, too bad.
No secret room.
If it even is able to teleport me to the secret room.
Maybe it only teleports me to known areas.
Red patch.
Chance to gain damage up for the current room each time you take damage.
I mean, it's better for the room I'm about to enter instead of the key thing.
So I can switch it back afterwards.
Yeah.
We're gonna switch it back after this.
It's Dingle!
Alright.
Let's kill a little guy.
Little piece of shit.
Oh, no.
Flinging poop at me.
Taunting me.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, come on.
You know, I'm gonna destroy this poop.
It's annoying me.
It's not even doing anything!
Dingle!
Come on!
They're not gonna charge me or something.
Okay.
Very nice.
Baby bottle.
No, Tropicamide.
Tear size and range up.
That is always good.
We also have this room.
Whoa!
Do I get the PhD or do I take the Masters?
Uh, wait, this one costs more.
Ooh!
Interesting.
Mmm.
I'm gonna try this.
Damage and tears up!
Hell yeah!
Should we go more?
Should we go crazy?
Get the PhD?
I wanna see what it does.
You unlocked Krampus.
False PhD?
Oh, no.
Plus one black heart.
Converts most good pill effects into bad pill effects.
Identifies pills before using them.
Consuming any stat down pill will also grant a permanent damage up.
Oh, wow.
Interesting.
Consuming most other pill types will also spawn a black heart.
That is very interesting.
It's a bad trip.
But what does that do, though?
Yeah, I don't know what just happened.
I have no clue what just occurred.
Alright, thanks.
Yes, we're moving on.
We have no red hearts left.
We totally just sold our soul to the devil.
Oh, man.
This is gonna be rough, isn't it?
Curse of the blind!
What?
What do you mean?
You got the wrong guy.
Nice.
Oh, I still got hit.
You gotta be kidding me.
I really tried to dodge that.
I did my best.
No suspicious rocks in here.
Everything looks to be above board.
Let me try this.
Ho, ho, ho!
Look at that!
I wonder if luck affects this.
Oh, it was right here.
That's funny.
I can't get to that.
If I could fly, though, now that would be great.
Man, it feels good to actually have some damage.
Very nice.
That's a big one.
I'm gonna run towards him and make accelerated shots.
Oh, wow, he's still alive.
Okay.
Oh, no keys!
No way.
Oh, no, I forgot to bring my rusted key!
Oh, shit!
That would have probably solved that problem.
All right.
My range is really good, though.
Phenomenal range.
Ah, too bad.
No, I can't even get inside the treasure room.
This one's open, though.
No!
Fuck, I need keys!
I have never needed more keys than right now.
Okay, this guy, he's the most dangerous.
Oh, come on.
Well, these red hearts are useless to me now.
Nope, not going in there.
That's a bad idea.
No!
Don't remind me that I don't have keys.
Let me go back down.
Man, I need keys.
Come on, come on, come on.
There's gotta be one somewhere.
Or ten.
I mean, sure, I'll take coins.
Weird room, isn't it?
Maybe if I extinguish these in a certain combination, a secret door appears.
That could only be unlocked with that photograph thing we found.
Imagine if I just called it, like, completely.
Fuck, I can't even go in there and use all my money!
Dude, what a waste of a floor.
So much potential just up in the smoke.
Or in the air, I mean.
That is, like, the most blue-balled I've ever been.
Careful.
Is he gonna charge?
At some point he's gonna start charging.
Is it now?
What?!
He predicted my movement!
Crazy stuff.
Huh?
What is it?
Why did that just happen?
Question mark.
Gonna lick them all!
Lick the bandages?
Ooh, okay.
That's disgusting.
Well, I really don't want to leave this floor behind, but...
What a waste.
There's like six chests or something I could have opened.
These guys are actually so tanky.
A key!
Nice.
Okay.
Hey, very nice!
Oh my god.
Oof.
What's that?
Oh, the tick!
We can't get rid of that if we take it.
Restores one red heart and removes 15% health.
I mean, it's not bad.
I kind of like it.
What was the red patch?
Gain damage up.
Oof.
Oh wow.
Oh my fucking god!
Ah!
This is death.
I'm out.
See ya, nerd!
All those spiders, it's just, it's over.
Man, these rooms are gonna kill me.
It's too difficult for me.
I think we're at the end here.
Come on, man.
Ah, I can't heal.
The deal.
Oh, wow, wow, wow.
Oh!
How am I still alive?
Dammit.
I mean, I guess there's a chance we run into the boss room with the teleport.
That would be kind of scary.
Safety cap.
Chance of finding a pill as a room clear?
More chance to add an additional pill.
Oh, you know what?
I need those.
I need pills.
Absolutely.
No, not this room!
Okay, it's not that bad, actually.
They die fast.
Kill them!
The way you came jumping at me.
Just stay at range.
Play it safe.
What?
Oh, I can't walk on the red shit!
Fuck, man.
What is it with me finding all these trinkets?
No, I don't need that.
I need to gamble right now.
We gotta get something good out of this.
Come on.
Don't you eat all my money?
Fuck you!
Give me the good stuff!
The bean!
At least it's a fart that poisons enemies and deflects, I mean...
No!
How about you?
You gonna give me something?
There's a heart!
This one.
Try again.
Like, he's...
It is a scam.
I mean, we know that.
Oi!
Okay, at least we can take two hits now.
Uh, this one?
No.
Yo!
So, wait, whatever he's showing down there is not actually what you're gonna get.
Not only is it a scam, it's a misleading scam as well.
Okay.
Awesome.
How about a blue heart or something?
That's what I really want.
Or a black heart?
I'll take both.
Hey, okay!
Some keys?
Can't complain about that.
Too bad.
I'm scared of being too close to him because he also spawns a bomb sometimes.
Come on, man.
Unlucky.
Dude, our drip is actually on point again.
The face mask with the hair, it fits.
We're gonna blow this guy up at the end.
With all the money we've given him, I wonder if blowing him up will somehow increase the chance of something good coming out.
More keys?
Last one.
Let it be good.
Dammit.
Okay, time to die.
Whoa!
Speed down, more damage.
I'm already kind of slow.
0.6 damage, though.
Nah, it's not worth it.
But wait a minute.
Something about eating pills now also does something good, right?
What was it?
This one.
Consuming any stat down pill will also grant a permanent damage up.
Consuming most other pill types will also spawn a black heart.
But what do you mean other pill types?
I don't... there's no black heart, what a fucking lie.
Hey!
That's good.
Uh, you need to be blown up, too.
Oh, no.
Okay.
Uh, let's do a...
Let's go to the treasure room.
Yep.
Oh, no.
Fuck!
I'm gonna die!
Holy...
Water room.
I panic easily.
We can even go in here.
Ooh.
Let me in.
Chemical peel.
Increases the damage of tears fired from Isaac's left eye.
Okay, okay.
I mean, that's just the damage up, I guess.
That's not gonna help me at all.
Hmm.
Let's do this.
All right, well, let's do the boss.
Not this guy!
I'm dead.
Oh, it's not the wall, it's different.
No, no, it is this guy.
He's gonna jump three times.
He spawned spiders?
Say what now?
Come on, come on, kill him!
Yes, yes.
Huge.
What's that?
More health?
Yes!
Massive.
All right, all right.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Wait, there's a room we're missing.
Uh, nah, let's go.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Oh!
No, no, I can't, I can't.
Can I?
Should I?
Fuck!
It's Krampus!
That's the Christmas guy!
Oh my god.
Yeah!
Head of Krampus has appeared now.
What's that?
A lump of coal.
My Christmas present!
I told you it was Christmas.
Makes tears increase in damage and size the farther they travel.
Really?
Oh yeah, slightly, I guess.
Okay.
Cool.
Wait, is there a secret in the Krampus room?
Okay.
Uh, let's go.
Moving on.
We're gonna get an extra heart now, too.
Yeah, huge.
Yoink!
This may have been a mistake.
Nope, it's fantastic.
Okay.
Not the big room.
Oh, come on.
I think a general rule to follow in this game is if an enemy's jumping, you move as far away as you can.
Not just slightly out of the way.
Go as far away as you can, otherwise you're gonna get hit by a random projectile as they land.
Wow, wow, wow, wow, wow.
Ooh, another speed down pill.
No, we can't become too slow.
It's too risky.
The bomber boy.
More bombs, bombs explode in a large cross shape pattern.
Ah, that's gonna kill me, though.
Isn't it?
Too risky?
Oh, I thought it was a trinket.
Oh, okay.
I'm poor.
Is that a boomerang?
Or a croissant?
Or a worm?
There's an exactly 33% chance of it being either one of those.
Oh, this is gonna be an awkward one.
Get up!
Nice.
Come here.
And now...
Let's go down here.
Thanks!
Whoa, holy crap.
Wow, blue hearts.
Fucking getting stuck in all the corners.
This room is crazy!
Oh!
How am I alive?
Spawns two soul hearts?
Even more?
Sure.
I'll take it.
Wow.
Damn, that room was a challenge.
All right.
Let me teleport.
Okay, so now I'm here.
Ah, we gotta go through here.
This one is a tough one.
Mom!
All right, after one another!
Pull me back to the start.
Okay, let's go do this one, I guess.
Yeah, you like that?
Bummer man style.
What, what, what, what?
Okay, okay.
I thought they were invisible there for a second.
Or Dingle lookalike.
The hangman grants flight for the room!
That is interesting.
Oh, yo, yo, yo, I saw that coming, actually.
Out of the way.
Nice, we finally cleared this room.
Teleport again.
I love teleporting, it's so much fun!
You don't know where you're gonna be.
Question is, where do I want flight?
I was gambling a little bit there.
Here.
Oh, come on.
They masterfully dodged that one.
Oh, this is where we gain flight.
Actually, is it worth it?
I can just use a key.
Oh, right!
I can use the new explosion thingy to get a lot of rocks.
Very nice.
Unfortunate place to be.
I want to go to the room on the very right over here that I didn't explore before, but I have to be careful because I'm going through the room with the gravity.
And the gravity is bad.
Okay, here we go, here we go.
Oh, master gamer!
Wow, oh, it's mom!
I'm getting deja vu right now.
No!
Fuck you, mom!
Not again!
All right, master gamer moment, here we go.
Oh, master gamer!
Oh, mom!
I'm getting deja vu.
Don't you grab me, I'm gonna keep moving!
You didn't get me this time, did you?
I'm gonna keep moving just in case mom is still here.
Mom's disgusting feet.
Okay.
Wow, Jesus!
How do you dodge that?
Okay.
Oh, these are not normal projectiles, they're like coming up from above.
It's artillery.
Nice.
These ones.
Good.
I have a feeling, guys, right there.
Never mind.
Yo, if there's a tiny enough room, I can use this new bomb effect to check multiple walls at the same time.
Now, is that genius or what?
Okay, okay, okay.
I have a feeling right here.
Shit!
My feelings are kind of off today.
Usually they're on point.
Oh no, going backwards, I can't do that.
Oh, I can!
Very nice.
No, not again!
Get me out of this room.
Why is it always that room?
Take me to the secret room.
Now we're talking.
Yeah, okay.
Fuck!
I almost got hit again.
Surely here.
Okay, hold on.
Where is this stupid secret room?
I mean, it could be behind the room over here, but I'm not gonna...
Nah, I don't want to lose my blue heart.
It's too valuable.
It's time to leave.
Wait a second.
I also had a shop.
I'm gonna buy this one.
Champion belt!
It was none of what I said.
Alright, increases champion monster spawns by 15%.
Ah, man, I wish I had not to buy that heart, but I don't.
Okay.
I gotta start donating to that machine as well.
I feel like I haven't done that in ages.
Maybe from now on that'll be the main thing I'll do.
The Fallen!
Okay.
He looks like Krampus.
Lost my blue hearts.
What's this?
Brimstone.
Blood laser barrage?
That sounds good.
Replaces Isaac's tears with a charged beam attack.
Beam becomes larger and deals additional damage.
Oh!
We have become Azazel!
What the fuck?
Wait, what?
Oh my god, it's infinite range?
No way!
Okay.
Very cool!
This just became a lot more interesting.
Oh no.
Oh, nice.
Dude, I have nailed that every single time I did it.
If that isn't a sign that I'm becoming a god gamer at this game, then I don't know what is.
Like, that is incredible.
Five times in a row or something.
Alright, it's time to leave.
Let's do it.
This is the mom floor.
I'm gonna pre-charge.
Azazel strategies.
Oh my god, it's so good!
Oh, okay, okay, okay.
Get lasered!
Get lasered, nerds!
Dude, the infinite range is kind of broken as hell.
I love it!
We gotta play careful.
I can't be too overconfident now.
That is a surefire way to, you know, mess it up.
Look at me go.
Okay.
Destroy all the fires.
It is weird not being able to fly when you have this ability, though.
It feels all wrong.
Oh, it's so good!
The secret room!
Show me the secrets.
Why are there so many flies in here?
Oh, yeah!
I don't know why I did that, but I just did.
You can go two ways now.
Fuck me!
Yo!
Yeah, sweep it!
What a sweep.
Amazing sweep.
Wow!
Temperance, sponsored blood donation machine.
I mean, sure.
That hit me?
I thought I was out of range.
Okay.
Whoa!
Wait, what's this one?
Ranch flight.
Oh!
I also had another card that I left behind somewhere.
No, maybe this was it.
I mean, I don't need flight in here.
Oh!
I don't know where they are.
I'm just going to do this.
Sweep the room.
Oh, they're dead.
Okay, okay.
Nothing.
Oh, no, this thing's going to move.
Maybe if I do this and then go...
No, gosh.
Oh, yeah.
Let me in.
Pills.
Let me read it.
Minus tears, more damage.
So, wait, that's at tech speed.
How would that work with this?
I mean, it's tears down, so it should be overall bad, I guess, right?
Mom's toenail.
During combat, dropping the trinket will cause Mom to stomp on its location?
Wait, how do I drop a trinket?
Why can't I see my goddamn controls in the middle of the game?
Uh...
What do I have now?
More pills?
Additional pill chests?
I mean, I like that.
I guess there's a chance we get good pills, right?
Yeah, I don't need that.
Oh, my God.
This is actually a move speed check, if you think about it, that room.
Whoa!
Booster pack!
Sup, dude?
Ho, ho, ho!
Ho,
ho, ho, ho!
Okay.
And that was it, okay, got it.
Two of clubs, doubles, I6 bombs.
Ooh, massive!
Sixteen times the bombs!
Two red hearts, I don't need that.
Uh, high priest, that's the foot coming down?
Two soul hearts, that's nice.
I enjoy that.
Reveals the map?
Wait, let me see if it's worth it here.
Can I see the map?
So, we've already found the secret room, so I think it's not worth it on this floor.
Yeah.
Actually, I kind of want to bring...
Ah, that's a tough one.
Right, it's flight, is there anywhere where I need flight?
Maybe I'll think about it.
Yeah.
And this one was the two red hearts.
Oh, okay.
Let's go down here.
Man, this ability is actually crazy.
That was a crazy ability.
Okay, range down, but more damage.
But wait, don't I have infinite range?
Yeah!
Hell yeah!
Look at me go!
Oh, that was an easy room.
Mom?
Whoa, it's the skeletal mom foot!
That's new.
Ice cube!
For some reason, I can't see the description on it.
Oh, there we go.
What's this?
Amnesia.
Gives Isaac curse of the lost, spawns one black heart.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
That's gonna hide my minimap, right?
I'm not gonna use it yet, then.
What is this?
Cube baby, kick it!
All right, it's gonna damage enemies, I guess.
Oh, it follows me.
Oh, okay!
Very cool.
I have a feeling.
My feeling was wrong.
Wait, I have another feeling.
I knew there was gonna be an enemy there.
That's what I was feeling.
I'm back here.
That's actually okay.
I'm gonna go to that last room up here.
I can just immediately kick the thing.
Oh, wait, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
There's a chest up here, it seems.
Wait, I have an idea.
Can I block this guy with this?
Amazing!
All right, this was it.
Nothing interesting there.
Actually, I'm fine.
This way.
And that's...
No, there's more.
I don't wanna go through here.
The ice cube is funny.
Is there anything else about it?
Apply slow to enemies it touches, freezes, enemies it kills.
Let's spend some money.
So what is this thing?
This is not just the Uber key.
This is different.
Mom's key, better chest loot plus two keys.
Okay.
Doubles the amount of pickups dropped by most chests.
Wow!
Very cool.
Now we got the Uber key.
I'm gonna donate two here.
Dinner on me.
The coins are coming to me.
Thanks.
There's another room over here.
This room is going pretty well.
I mean floor.
Lovely.
Nice.
All right, are we ready?
The lovers is gonna spawn hearts.
There were a couple other things, though.
That I wanted to grab over here.
Before I start.
Where were the cards at down there?
Man, it's quite the distance to go.
Maybe it's a bit pedantic of me to do this.
Little try-hard.
No, it took me all the way back, dammit.
Ah, actually, wait, wait.
That's too bad.
I took a gamble, didn't pay off.
Up here.
There's definitely at least one card down here that I really want.
Grant's flight, I think it was this one.
Yeah.
The world, I like that.
We're gonna use it on the next floor.
That way we can see the secrets.
Ah, not that room.
One thing, though, I think we need a bit more speed.
We're kind of slow.
Having more speed would be nice.
All right, here we go.
Watch me lock.
All right, mom.
That's a lot of damage I'm doing there.
Wait, what am I taking damage from?
Is foot coming down?
We got it, we got it.
Very nice.
Mom's lipstick.
More range.
Well, that's useless.
I'll take it anyway.
Okay.
Uh, wait a minute.
Check this out.
We can't leave this room.
But I can teleport.
So can we enter again?
What's gonna happen?
Did I just softlock myself?
Wait a minute.
No, the door's here.
Interesting.
Huh.
Okay.
And then the door disappears.
All right.
Interesting.
I wonder why that is.
Why does the room close off?
It doesn't always do that.
Maybe just to make it harder.
Oh, this is so good for this.
Man, this laser is insane.
Unbelievable.
Oh wait, amnesia?
What was that?
Curse of the Lost spawns a black heart.
Let's try it.
Amnesia.
But wait, now the world is gonna be useless.
Maybe it is.
Wait, if I use this, I think it's also gonna unlock...
No, it's not gonna automatically open the doors, though.
I messed up bad.
I shouldn't have done this.
This was a mistake.
Damn it!
Yeah, I did a dumb thing.
Are you a wizard?
Tears fire diagonally for 30 seconds?
What do you mean?
Like in all directions?
Or...
Let me try it.
A black heart!
Oh, okay, so it actually didn't do anything.
Oh, that's weird.
Okay.
Wait, this room is...
Oh no, I'm gonna be so lost, guys.
There's a door here.
Peace.
Ah,
challenge room.
We like that.
Hills.
Ahoy!
Oh my god, the laser is crazy!
It is actually unreal!
We also have a pill here.
I'm excited!
Speeds up everything for the room and three additional times!
Spawns one black heart.
Okay.
Less tears.
More damage.
And this one is...
another speed.
Does it stack?
Are we stacking?
I don't think it's stacking.
Mom, mom, mom, mom, mom, mom.
Another one, probably?
Ah, third one!
Mom!
Come on!
Since when do you have three feet?
Come on, that doesn't make any sense.
There's more, right?
There's more.
Okay, we're done, we're done.
Okay, okay.
I'm not gonna enter that room.
I'm kind of lost.
This way...
Wait, there's nowhere to go.
Huh?
I think there's a secret over here.
I was wrong.
Here.
Yeah!
I told you!
I'm always right.
Boom, baby!
Getting some money?
Right, I have no map.
Why am I trying?
Wait, do I have to go through here?
Shit, I'm really lost.
Whoa!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I saw that coming.
What's this room?
That's suspicious.
A pill?
Less speed?
More?
No, no, no.
I want speed.
Speed is very important.
I want speed to me right now.
Now I need a shop.
Maybe there's no shops when you're in the uterus or whatever.
I mean, who would set up shop in this place, right?
Uh-oh, uh-oh.
More feet?
Oh, this is lovely for this.
Look at that!
No problem.
There's a pill over there.
A
flat file causes all spikes on obstacles, doors and chests to retract.
Whoa!
Is that a, uh, it is a trinket?
That sounds pretty good.
Yeah, fuck that.
I don't need any more pills.
I'm good on that.
Mom?
Look at those hands.
Or feet, whatever.
Man, what about all my money?
Okay, so this is the boss.
Get him.
What's this?
Myo sodus.
Up to four uncollected pickups from the previous floor will spawn in the starting room of a new floor.
There's no new floors.
Okay.
I actually can't see the map and I'm already super lost, so let's just go.
Wish me luck.
Wait, what?
Blastocyst?
I thought this was the final boss.
Oh, shit.
I mean, it's going pretty well, I guess.
Pentagram.
More damage!
Nice.
Leviathan!
What?
What happened?
Oh, Leviathan three of three.
I'm flying!
Am I?
I am flying.
But I can't fly through this, apparently.
What the?
Oh, there's also this room.
Ooh, what is this?
Rotten?
Oh, guys.
I am tempted.
But if I take this, I'm going to lose both of my red hearts and then we have a whole other floor to get through.
I don't think it's a good idea.
I'm just going to leave it.
Yeah.
Actually, let me...
Okay.
That doesn't do anything.
I can actually go back if I want to.
Should I?
I mean, my room is... or not my room, my map is still gone.
Let's just go.
Here's a flower.
And a peepee.
Horrible dreams.
I wonder if you can unlock good dreams at some point.
Uh-oh.
Wait, we can fly!
That's crazy.
Dude, we're actually Azazel right now!
Isn't that funny?
All roads lead to Azazel.
Wow, this one's going to make red chests appear.
Oh, this is the abortion thingy, right?
Wirecoat hanger, tears up.
Okay.
Okay, so tears up is definitely charge speed.
Look at this.
Yeah.
I think this is what I unlocked last time, actually.
Was this the very last item I unlocked?
I think so.
Oh, no, not the eyes!
Removed my heart!
No!
It's mom again.
There's more.
Money bags.
I could teleport.
But I'm not gonna.
Consolation price.
Is that increased based on which everyone is the lowest?
Yeah.
I gained more charge speed.
Very good.
Jesus Christ, the damage is off the wall!
There's a secret here.
You can't tell me there's not.
Okay, there is not.
So they could tell me.
The frozen baby is just weird, man.
No reason not to blow everything up.
I have so many bombs.
We're gonna be mega looking for secrets now.
Man, I love being at range.
Wow, come on.
Really?
Oh, dude.
Wait, there's a button.
By the way, I installed the mod that Frank made for me.
It's not working.
I did install it.
Just saying.
Maybe I need to activate it in the menu or something, I'm not sure.
Uh-oh, what's this?
Uh-oh!
I'm scared, I'm not gonna collect that, fuck that.
Nope, nope, nope, nope, absolutely not.
Absolutely not.
I don't know what it does, it could ruin everything.
I'm so scared of those rooms now.
Oh, God.
We're chilling.
That's the boss there.
Matchbook.
More Blackheart, more bombs.
Matchstick trinkets.
Damn, I have a lot of bombs.
I do have so many bombs.
Good.
Oh!
Frozen!
Thank you, baby.
Look how OP I am!
I'm just crushing.
And here.
Ah!
Interesting, what do I do here?
Poopy butts.
These guys think they can shoot lasers at me, I shoot lasers at them.
Do we have more survivors?
We do.
Okay.
Now what?
Uh, there's a challenge room.
Minus one ra- Yeah, gimme that!
We don't like that, that's bad.
Ah,
we can't enter here.
But wait, let me brute force my way in.
No?
Maybe it ain't possible.
Man, I wish I could donate my money.
But I can't.
Now, one thing I can try.
Wait, is one now?
Oh yeah, it was one before as well.
Really?
Oh, oh, oh!
Not in our mind.
Here we go, you ready?
Here we go!
Uh, we don't need the file anymore.
Guess we don't need this one.
What is that?
Yeah, it's fine.
Here we go!
Wish me luck!
It's gonna be easy though.
Oh, the little eyes need to die, right?
There we go.
Wow.
I'm taking a lot of damage here.
Just shoot her down, shoot her down.
Nice.
We did it!
What's it gonna be this time?
Huh!
We got pulled into the chest!
Alrighty!
That was a nice one!
Everything is terrible, the game just got harder?
No!
It's already hard enough as it is.
How come there's no Xs on it anymore?
Usually there's like Xs showing how many wins I have.
What?
Okay, okay.
Let's try something new.
Uh, Eden was kind of cool.
I kind of like Eden.
I like the fact that it's a little random what you start with, that's cool.
Did we try Eve again?
Dead bird and Whore of Babylon.
So obviously she is lustful.
She's into the whole sex thing.
But how does that actually play out in the game?
Last time I had her?
Not like that.
But last time I had her, when I ran into an enemy, she got turned into a demon.
And I don't understand why, but I'm curious to find out why.
Let's do it.
Get in the box!
Mom, pull us in the box!
Okay, right.
It's not a phase, Mom.
I remember her damage being pathetic.
But so far it's not that bad.
It's sort of average, I would say.
And every time these guys take damage, I keep thinking I take damage.
This is the type of voice that you would have as a Whore of Babylon, you know?
Not true.
That's only in Japanese versions.
Okay, what's this?
We don't know?
Shot speed up!
Nice!
Okay.
I feel it.
It's a good feeling.
He's... Also, I start with nothing, it seems.
Do I have any items?
Nothing, okay.
So how does the Whore aspect play out?
That's what I want to know.
Okay, that's a bomb.
Get kited.
Actually, wait, let me play this smart.
I'm gonna blow this guy up over here.
Ah, I didn't want to blow him up there, but okay.
This level is very much made for kiting them.
Obviously, we go into the treasure room first.
Anything else would be insanity.
Look at these guys.
I haven't seen these flies before.
They move erratically.
Little green buggers.
This is the steak it's going to... something with Dracula, probably.
Stigmata.
Damage and HP up.
Wow!
What a great item!
That just makes me so much better.
Lovely.
I love the Stigmata.
Come on, blow up over here.
Actually, that is fine.
God, I can't hit him.
That was close.
Very nice, getting all resources.
I haven't even been looking for the tinted rocks yet.
I should keep an eye out.
Uh-oh.
This was gonna... Yeah, I knew it.
I knew it.
I can't deal with the spiders.
They're too fast.
Like, how do you dodge that?
It's insanity.
Mr. Dolly.
Oh no, it's the opposite of me!
Dolly Parton.
Is that a reference to that?
Tears, range, three random heart pickups.
Oh, check this out.
We're gonna go...
Oh no, wait, never mind.
It doesn't matter.
I was gonna say, let's pick up the black heart first, then the red heart, so that the black heart is protected by the red heart.
But it doesn't work like that, of course.
It's just healing.
Oh, that looks cool.
Look at that.
We gotta make money.
I wanna see what that is.
Really badly, actually.
Oh God, don't blow up next to me.
Fantastic.
Teleport to the shop.
Ah, that's kind of useless.
Unless we find a room where we take damage upon entering and yada, yada.
Actually, there is a room like that up here.
And it's worth it.
Nice!
My black hearts are protected now.
And now I use this.
Look at me go.
Look at that efficiency, people.
You know what?
Let's take 135.
Not a breakpoint, okay.
I bet the next one is 150.
Okay.
So far, so good.
The whore is doing good here.
We're gonna pop up there.
Very good.
So far, it's been clean and flawless.
Oh, I spoke too soon.
Man, that was close, though.
Oh, nice.
I love getting the meat.
The meat is solid.
So there's a timer on this floor.
I do wonder what that means.
You know what it could mean?
Maybe it's like...
This is your... it's like a running against your ghost self, like in racing games.
Maybe it's telling me this is your fastest one yet or something, you know?
Ah, that doesn't make any sense, actually.
Ah, never mind.
Ah!
I really wanna press that button.
I'm gonna do it.
Oi!
Okay, okay.
Very good.
I do need money.
Bomb for a key?
I don't think so.
Okay.
I'm really trying to pay attention to the area around my character more than just my character.
So I can actually see projectiles and stuff.
That's my big weakness.
This way.
Oh!
What is that?
An angry worm.
That's a mobile game.
Oh!
Oh, very nice!
Thank you, sir!
You know what?
Can you help me over here, actually?
Again?
Ah, it's probably the same room, I guess.
Come on, help me blow shit up over here.
Okay, fine.
Money.
I'm gonna blow you up.
No!
So unlucky.
Oh, god!
Ooh!
These flies are not joking around.
Wait, there's a bird on me!
Oh!
Is that the bird that came with me?
The character?
Why did it spawn?
Oh, we're not done in here.
I wonder what the condition was for that to happen.
Maybe there's a chance upon taking damage?
Or something like it?
Juicy sack.
Following Familia that generates a trail of slo- This one is good.
I like that one.
This means we can kite quite well.
Over here.
The bird is gone now.
Yeah, going to the creep.
Now the- Oh, yeah, so the bird spawned again when it took damage.
So I think it is related to taking damage.
Now the bird is gone, so it's per room.
I see.
Isaac!
A bar of soap?
Or what?
What is that?
I kind of want to buy the pill, though.
Ooh, maybe we can save up and get the bar of soap.
I think I may like that more.
We have a couple rooms left.
Everything went dark?
It means there's a secret.
Maybe here?
No?
Okay.
Ah, let's do the boss.
No, you have 18 now!
Whoa!
That fits very well with the whore as well.
Let's go.
Gimme.
Eraser!
Erase thy enemy.
Throws the eraser in the direction of your choice.
It's an active.
Upon striking an enemy, the eraser will instantly destroy it and all copies of it.
And prevent that enemy type from spawning again for the rest of the run?
Whoa!
Does not erase bosses and only deals minor damage to them.
Can be thrown once per floor.
Holy shit!
Cannot be recharged through normal methods.
Okay.
That sounds incredibly good.
Now I really got to think about which... So wait, how does this work?
Do I have to...
Let's see.
The direction of your choice.
So I guess when I spawn it, I'm gonna hold it over my head and then I shoot it with the arrows.
I hope that's how it works, otherwise I'm just gonna fuck it up immediately.
Too bad I got it now and the floor is cleared.
Man.
What enemy type would I like to get rid of?
Whoa, what a dodge though, what a dodge!
That was beautiful.
Oh god.
Yeah, the bird spawned as soon as I took damage.
I saw it.
Confirmed.
You know what, maybe I hate these little guys.
Okay, I'm holding it.
Did I actually do it or did they disappear because the boss died?
I'm not sure what just happened.
I think I did it.
Magic scab, luck, health and healing.
Okay.
Oh, we also have a special room here.
I have lots of hearts to use.
Ooh, I'm gonna get both!
But first, remove the evil fires.
I'm getting both, they're so cheap.
No money?
Wow.
He accepts your offering, goat hit.
Looks cool.
Guarantees all devil deals appear and remain open.
Contract from below.
Wealth, but at what cost?
Dude, we're going full demon mode!
Decreases the likelihood of a room clear reward by 33%.
Doubles the room clear reward when earned.
Oh.
I guess that's better all in all.
Okay.
Well, the problem is, uh, devil deals.
I don't have infinite hearts, you know, so what's the point of those?
Unless you find like a million items that heal you up to full.
Oh, God.
How much HP do you have, sir?
That is crazy.
You got pills.
What does that do?
Balls of steel.
I think I read about it once before, but I forgot what it did.
Also, I can't see my hearts!
Why is that?
Huh?
Giant cell taking damage spawns many familiar.
Sure.
Why not?
I'm not doing that much damage.
Also, what about the Whore of Babylon?
When is the Whore coming out?
No!
The bird
is here.
I'm actually just going to blow things up.
Okay, that was a waste.
I can't get over there, unfortunately.
Oh, this may actually be kind of difficult.
Oh, my bird is doing so much damage!
The bird is kind of cracked!
Okay, the bird is really good.
Mr. Boom, reusable bomb body.
Spawns a large bomb.
I like a razor more.
I mean, we can use this and switch it over and then switch back, I guess.
Yeah, why not?
No, I'm kind of scared because I can't see my HP, but we had a lot, I think.
We were chilling.
Oh, no, there's spikes.
Ah, come on.
Ah, not worth it.
Shit.
You know what?
These guys, I hate them.
We're going to do this.
Ah!
I missed!
Unreal.
And I took a bunch of damage.
It couldn't have been worse.
They cannot get worse.
Here, bombs.
That didn't do anything.
All right, that was good.
Dude, I kind of nailed that.
That was really well played if I do say so myself.
That was amazing.
There we go.
That's a lot.
I wish I could soap them.
Wait, didn't I erase these guys?
Motherfucker.
So they did despawn.
I thought I erased them.
Shit.
Unbelievable.
Uh-oh, I'm dead.
I'm kidding.
There's no problem.
I seem to remember these guys being tougher.
I didn't mean to go in here.
I miss walked.
This was a mistake.
I don't know how much HP I have.
This could be the end.
Wish me luck.
Okay, we're not dead.
But it's not looking good.
Okay, one is down.
Wow.
I'm kind of a sniper though.
Yeah!
Car battery?
Or a heart?
I can buy both.
Hey, it is actually a car battery.
Amazing.
One of the few times the icon looks like what it is.
Doubles the effects of most active item activations.
So I can use my soap again or what?
Maybe not.
One key?
I mean, one coin?
That's it.
Don't need my money.
Put it in there.
We got to start working on that.
Okay, south.
Oh my god.
Bullet hell type situations and I falter immediately.
That's when it's going to go wrong.
How am I going to do this?
Just how am I going to do this?
Okay, one is down.
Oh, look at me.
I wish I could soap these guys.
They need to be cleansed.
I guess it's time for the boss.
It's the husk.
I don't think I've ever seen this guy actually.
Ah, maybe I have.
I don't know how much HP I have, I just got to play it well.
Watch for the...
projectiles here.
Keep my distance.
My bird is here though.
Yeah, my bird is doing well.
The belt.
Okay, so we did not have full on red hearts.
I can't see my health.
Here's the plan.
We're going to go back and grab the remaining healing.
Wherever we can find it.
Oh, okay, so that's definitely at least one heart we have.
More than one heart actually.
Okay, that was it, huh?
I don't know, man.
Oh, no.
Should I do it?
Wait.
Uh-oh, uh-oh!
I see you, I see you.
Okay, thank God.
Black powder.
Leave behind a powder trail that spawns damaging pentagrams when circles are drawn.
I don't like this.
I hate it.
I'm moving on.
Fuck that noise.
Yikes.
That sounds horrible.
Curse of the Lost?
Oh, we can't see the map.
Oh, no, I can't get to that.
I can maybe get to that.
Can I get to that?
No.
I think this rock needs to be here.
But it's not.
Shit.
I'm trying to pay attention to the layout now, so this is where I started.
I went north, let's go right.
Man, what is it with these rooms that I can't do anything about?
Nice.
I'm doing surprising amounts of damage.
Doesn't feel like I'm doing much damage when I look at the stats, I mean.
I somehow did that without taking a single damage.
That's amazing.
This room is...
Yeah, no thanks.
I can see my hearts now.
I have three, okay.
I could actually have taken something then last time.
I was a little too scared, though.
This is awkward.
Yeah, come on bird, carry me.
Carry me!
Nice, thanks.
Get him, get him.
You got it.
What a horrible...
Man, I wish I could read that before it disappears.
It's like a fucking half a second you get for that.
I erased them!
No more of those guys.
Okay.
Batteries.
Wait, my bird is still here.
It persists between rooms, it seems.
It didn't do that earlier.
What?
Why is that?
I'm kind of in danger here.
A foot.
Lucky foot.
Oh, is that what Lazarus has?
Plus one block converts bad pill effects into good pill effects.
Increases chance of getting room clear rewards.
Increases chance of winning rewards from bums and arcade games.
All right.
Okay.
So just very lucky stuff.
Get lucky.
But I think it's almost over here, we have half a heart.
And no way to heal.
It's not looking good.
I'm going to start blowing things up.
Nothing, huh?
At least my bird is with me all the time.
Maybe it's because I'm very low HP.
I'm not sure.
Oh, no.
Killing fast?
Oh, nice bird.
Nice bird.
I love you.
This bird is such a nice helper.
Uh-oh.
Yeah, okay.
Instantly over.
Rough.
The horror run didn't go too well.
I'll try one more time with the horror.
Oh, wow.
Immediately get an item here.
Cricket set.
Whoa!
That's crazy.
A lot of damage.
Very nice.
Now we're not hitting like a wimp anymore.
Uh, no bombs though.
Man, the art of not getting stuck in a corner is...
something of an art.
That was solid.
Okay.
And I explode.
Come on, man.
Oh, the bird made him explode.
The boss is here.
Yo, you know what?
Let's try something.
No, no, no, no.
Never mind.
I was about to do something dumb.
No supplies!
Good.
Now we have these floppy guys.
Still no bombs.
Dodge!
Nice.
Uh, check the rocks.
Nothing.
We gotta find damage now, because there's a multiplier on it.
Ooh, baby.
That can only go well.
Pill.
I would love a pill.
Okay, we're pretty much done here.
I'm not gonna go through that door.
Time for the boss.
Ah, this guy's easy.
Two good flies.
No problem.
We're chilling.
I don't have that much range, though.
Oi!
He pushed him towards me.
That was clean.
We got a mushroom.
More tears, less shot speed, one wealth, one red heart.
Or health.
Nice.
Good.
Movin' on!
So is Isaac just naked all the time, or how did he just sort of poop?
Like that.
I guess dreams don't make sense.
Definitely eating this.
Oh, useless.
What's with this room?
Weird.
Down here.
Yo!
Okay, he's only gonna go around that central part in the left.
Doesn't even stop.
Oh my god, oh my god!
Ah!
Fuckin' hell.
Dead end.
What did I take damage from?
I don't understand how I just took damage.
That was nothing.
Did I take damage because my bird popped out?
That's what it looked like.
No wait, the bird spawns because I take damage.
Oh, this is awkward as hell.
Oh, he explodes, huh?
What a weird room.
Ancient recall.
Uh, 40 damage to enemies in the room.
Do it now.
Kill him.
Magician's range and blood donation.
Nice.
All right, not too bad.
I'm trying to kite them in a circle now.
Teleport to the shop?
I could do that.
Oh, I want this one.
One additional item will appear in treasure.
Oh, I don't have enough money.
Would love that.
It's going pretty well so far, actually.
He's run.
Oh, treasure room.
Freezer baby.
That one is actually good.
Time for the boss.
Monster, I'm not even going to use my card here.
Did he actually just get frozen or...
I don't know whether I was stunned.
Look
how good that is.
Oh, man, that was clean as well.
I'm actually kind of killing it.
Oh, a new one.
Toothpicks.
Tears and shots speed up.
Whoa.
Just a good upgrade.
I like it.
I'm done here.
Those are some fat legs.
This mom ate processed food 100%.
Oh, get frozen, nerd.
Wait, why don't we just lose demon?
You saw that?
We just got minus on the demon modifier.
What did I do?
No!
How did I get hit by that?
That was so bad.
Okay.
Nice.
That's a solid upgrade as well.
Just like that.
Too bad I can't fly.
You want keys?
There's no way I'm giving you my keys.
Eat dirt.
My keys are valuable.
Get frozen.
Ah, fuck me.
These guys are so difficult.
The Skeletrons are nuts.
Get them out of here.
So many enemies in this room.
I kind of want to get that heart.
And I can.
Wait, there's a blue heart?
Thanks.
Huge.
Shade reaction.
That's fun.
What's that?
A new item.
Bloodshot eye.
A bloody friend.
It's a familiar.
Blocks enemy shots, steals contact damage, and fires shots at enemies.
Okay, okay.
Standards set up for a familiar.
Nothing spectacular there.
A pill.
I need it.
Oi!
That's nice.
Very good.
And what's this one?
Emergency contact.
Wants two mom's hands to damage and pin enemies.
That's an active item.
But I can't afford it.
Bad.
I'm going to come back for these hearts later in case I need it.
Not yet.
There we go.
Freeze him.
Okay.
I like this character, actually.
The bird is helping a lot when you get damaged.
All around good, I guess.
I don't know what the horror of Babylon means, though.
That's the big mystery.
Wow.
Oh, you're still alive.
That was so close.
Lovely.
Hey, this is for you.
What is that?
Endless nameless?
I'm stuck in a loop.
A chance to spawn a copy of a card pill of rune that was used?
Did it say pill as well?
So that means we have a good chance of getting another speed pill.
I like that.
I do.
Oh, we got frozen immediately.
And so far so good.
That was lucky.
Man, I got lucky there with the projectiles.
Stuy.
More damage multiplier.
But it's not really showing on my UI.
Maybe because it's just one eye.
But I'm curious to see how much more of a difference it makes.
Oi, oi, oi, that was bad.
My bird is here.
Is that copy?
Dead cat.
It's appeared in the basement.
What a horrible night.
So I can never read that in full.
What does it mean?
Fucking hate that they do that.
Grants nine extra lives.
But reduces red heart containers to one.
Ooh.
Oh.
Wait, why do I look like this now?
We are the ultimate demon lady now.
And we're fast.
What the frick is going on?
Oh yeah, freeze them all.
You're under arrest.
Hands up.
Chest.
I can't get that.
Man, I love the freezing effect.
So satisfying when they crack as well, the sound effect design on that.
Nice.
I'm shooting so many things.
So nine lives.
One HP.
It sounds really good, actually.
Oh,
that's going to be an ultimate freeze.
Arcade.
Nah, I've got one key left.
I don't want to waste it on that.
I'm shooting so many projectiles.
My familiars are shooting.
We have the bird out.
Wait a minute.
It's because I'm on low HP that the bird doesn't disappear now.
This is actually amazing, then.
Because I'm always going to be on low HP.
Isaac fires a laser from his mouth.
That's not exactly the effect I would put on the laser, but okay.
Second hand increases the duration of status effects.
Nah.
Status effects.
I don't think I need that.
I don't have any status effects.
Come on, birdie.
There you go.
I have good damage.
Boss time?
No, not yet.
There's a heart in here, apparently.
No, next room.
Oh, I missed that.
Neat.
Okay, so you want coins, you want bombs.
We can do a couple of these, I guess.
Okay, I don't like it.
We're going to blow them up.
Oh, nice.
And a secret reveal!
That was so worth...
Holy shit.
Oh, he...
Oh!
Oh, okay.
So if you try to blow that guy up, he's going to resist it because he's the bomb man.
Wait, we just gained demon.
Maybe it's when you perform, like, bad acts.
Then you become evil.
You become a demon.
Another heart.
Oh, yeah, look, look, look.
The bird is gone now because I have blue hearts.
So maybe I shouldn't have taken those blue hearts.
Nah, definitely worth it to take the blue hearts.
Come on.
Nope, no thanks.
I can't believe I got hit.
Try the spike.
Oh, the bird is back.
So maybe it's when you're at...
Let me see if the bird is still here.
It's not...
Okay, so I think it's when you're at 1 HP, specifically.
Then...
The magic happens.
Okay.
Time for the boss.
We're going to try and swoop the whoop in the boss.
Boss room.
I need to see exactly how that works.
So...
Why is it laser from his mouth?
I seem to remember this one going diagonally.
I could be wrong.
But the way it's described makes it sound like it's not diagonal.
You know what?
Don't hate money.
Yeah, 145.
Here we go.
Mega fatty.
Wait, what just...
Oh, did he pull me towards him?
I don't understand what's happening.
What is occurring?!
I have no idea what just happened.
Okay, there we go.
I tried to use that before, but then nothing happened when I clicked.
That was weird, man.
Okay, console...
Okay, so wait, wait.
Oh, wait, my demon just went down.
Why?
When I kill a boss, the demon...
Because killing bosses is considered a good act, maybe.
So let's see which stat increase we get here.
Pick up drops, one pick up that Isaac has the least of.
What's that?
Range.
Okay.
Nice.
That's good.
Yeah, we keep moving.
And we got demon mode activated again in the bottom left, and a lot of damage.
Wait, I wonder if we get extra damage?
That's one heart as well.
Let's do this one.
Oh god.
Oh, we're gonna definitely do this.
Oh, beautiful.
What?
Oh, right, I come back.
Oh no.
Wow, I died fast there, huh?
Well, I do have nine lives, or I have...
Now I have seven?
Oh my god.
That was a tough rune.
Yikes.
Ha ha ha!
Man, shmoop da boop!
It's actually solid.
It's pretty much like an Azazel on an active.
Killing bird.
Wait, what am I taking damage from?
Is it the fucking red stuff on the floor?
That's horrible.
I hate that.
What the fuck?
Oish.
Oh no.
This is actually kind of a scary rune.
Come on bird, kill him.
There you go.
Good job.
Oh, wow, man.
Being on one HP is crazy.
There's so much shit on my screen, I can't tell.
What is what?
Yeah, fuck that.
Oh, I can't leave!
No!
How can you avoid it?
Hello?
Just impossible.
This is not going well at all.
We got demon thingies here.
I don't think I've ever seen these before.
Oh, this room.
But I can't do anything.
So are you going to open the door for me?
Oh, the bird is taking care of it.
Good job bird.
Yeah.
Lovely.
My eyes itchy.
Can I touch the white stuff?
It seems like it.
Oh my god, oh my god, oh my god.
What is even happening on my screen?
So much shit on my screen, man.
Great.
Yeah, okay, okay.
Wow!
Insanity.
It's not going well.
Get him, bird.
Oh, man.
Scary.
I got no keys.
No keys at all.
No far so good.
The bird is such an MVP here.
No, I can't even go in there.
Aw, frick.
There's a room over here we can use.
Let's kill him.
No.
I just want one key.
Can I have that?
Not even a secret.
Maybe over here.
Oh, he's going to spawn a bunch of shit.
When he dies, it's going to be crazy.
Okay, we kind of managed that.
That's not too bad.
Wow!
Oh, man.
There's another one over here.
Get him, bird.
Thanks.
Man, that also despawns the...
Oh, nice.
We got a key.
That means we're going back here.
Oh, there's also a room.
No!
Wait, I baited it.
I baited it!
Insanity!
What a gamer.
That was insane.
The tactics coming into play here.
That just gave me so much boost and confidence.
That's a fly with shockwaves.
Distant admiration, attack fly.
I like that.
Distant orbital fly that deals contact damage.
Distant.
Oh, yeah, you are kind of distant, kind of.
Nice.
Let's go to the shop.
We are rich.
This is a must.
Oh, it's greed.
No problem.
That's a steam sale?
Yeah.
I wonder if there's a chance to trade my items later on somehow.
Like, you know, I gave you this item and I can choose from a selection or something.
Maybe that could be a thing.
We're actually here.
I'm going to shoot the Vuba the shit out of this guy, I think.
Beautiful.
Oh, yeah.
He's all flattened.
Oh, my God, please, please, don't do this.
Okay, okay.
Matchbook.
A black card.
Okay.
Do we have, like, a devil thing?
We don't have a devil.
Okay.
Moving on.
Okay, we got a hundred percent demon mode now somehow.
Maybe it's related to whether or not I found the demon room or not.
If I didn't find it, it's now a hundred percent.
You know, next time.
Just so I always find something at some point.
No suspicious rocks.
Mom!
Get frozen.
And a key that's huge.
You like keys?
Again?
Nice.
I'm going to the arcade because I am kind of rich.
You want bombs?
That means I shouldn't bomb you.
Oh, my God.
Thanks.
Good start.
Wow.
Wait, did my red fly just kill that?
They instantly die somehow.
Maybe it's my blue flies.
Yeah, it is my blue flies.
They're being wasted right now.
But it is what it is.
I just got to get away faster.
And he flew off to space and left me this.
Scatoli, fly love.
Okay, many fly enemies become less dangerous.
I love that.
I hate fly enemies.
Only I shall have the good flies.
This was good.
One of the best arcades I've had in a while.
And I've had quite a few, okay?
Oh, big guy.
Look at the reactions here.
Off the charts.
I'm going to destroy this guy so he can freeze everyone else.
Lovely.
Why are you going over there?
Nice.
That was a good room.
Dude, right here.
Nevermind.
How?
That's for you.
Boss?
You know what?
Why not?
Oh, it's mom!
Fuck!
Mistake!
I'm going to swoop it.
Focus.
Fuck!
That's too much shit.
I'm taking damage from all kinds of sources and I don't know what it is.
Yeah, get frozen!
What an ending!
Blue overalls.
PJs, you feel cozy.
Oh!
Look at all those hearts I just gained.
Heals all red hearts plus four soul hearts.
Nice.
Very cool.
Ah!
We got a demon deal.
My last red... wait!
Ah!
Mom!
Oh well.
Okay.
Well, shit.
Bro!
Come on.
Kill these guys.
I didn't even notice mom was in there.
Oh, this is a frozen fly.
Nice.
Beautiful.
The question is, we have not found a treasure room yet, so we should keep exploring here.
I'm going to bait this.
Look how I baited?
Oh!
Okay, never mind.
Play-doh.
All the random shit.
Yeah, I guess it's okay.
Ah, for fuck's sake!
I frickin' hate those rooms.
How do you not get hit by that?
This is just random bullshit go right now.
Three tomatoes?
I didn't even see that thing!
Ah!
Oh!
How did I not get hit there?
That was a close one.
I'm not going to get that one.
Yep.
Freeze him.
Cool.
Mom!
Look at all the stuff I'm shooting.
Just random colors.
It's like I'm puking out all kinds of stuff.
A binky.
More tears.
A soul heart sized down?
I like it.
That is solid.
Oh yeah, I got frozen nerd.
Cool, there's more though, yeah.
He's going to shoot lasers?
No, maybe that's not the guy.
Oh, he's doing that.
Scary.
He got frozen while flattened.
Oh wow.
The range on that.
A pulse worm causes tears to pulse in size?
Ah, is that good?
No.
My tears are mega huge without that.
That's horrible.
I'd rather not have it.
Okay, now.
Money room, and then we leave.
Four hearts left, by the way.
Or four lives, I should say.
It's getting a little dicey.
The sharp key.
Oh yeah, we have steam sail.
It's super cheap.
I mean, I'll take it for the keys.
Yeah.
And then I'll take the swoop back.
I'll even buy a key as well, and maybe this one too.
The tower.
Ooh.
Wait, I know what that is though.
I've read it before.
How come it's not shown?
Oh, because cards are randomized, I guess.
Tower, that is the one...
I think... No, I don't remember.
I think it's combat related.
It's going to do good things for me in combat.
Mining pick.
I have just enough.
Let's do it.
Notched axe.
Nice.
Notch.
Will the pickaxe press attack buttons to swing it?
It can break rocks and damage enemies, but has limited uses per floor.
Ha!
That sounds kind of nice, actually, but the swoop the swoop is even better.
The swoop the swoop is the way to go.
Let's go to the boss.
I have enough bombs to break rocks anyway, if I need to.
Wait, which way is it?
Over here.
Okay.
It's time for uterus, I think.
Wait, did our mom gift us that wig?
That's messed up.
Okay, it's the womb.
I don't know what the difference is, honestly.
Wait, how am I gonna... Oh, I see.
What?
I was at full HP, what do you mean?
That... I was at full HP.
Hold on, I can't take damage here.
Fuck!
What the fuck?
It does a full heart of damage?
Brother!
It's over!
Just kill me, end the run right here.
Insanity.
Oh, wow.
Yeah, I mean, I can barely see what's happening.
There's so much shit on my screen.
I'm gonna get hit by something and die.
Somehow I didn't.
Look.
Give me that.
Yeah, no thanks.
I freed them.
This is so over.
Look at all this crap!
Literally.
Oh, that's lovely.
Oh, I break them all.
We're gonna have to use swoop-de-loop defensively here.
Just to stay alive.
Oh, no, not this shit!
Wow.
What's happening?
Demon mode!
Demonic!
Demons are coming.
Super wrath?
That ain't good.
He's dropping big bombs.
Good, good, good, good, good, good, good, good.
Keys and bombs.
Go this way.
Weird room.
Oh, no.
We gotta swoop it.
I had to do it.
Wow!
I'm dead.
Oh, that's it.
We have one more life.
I thought that was it.
Wow.
Wow, wow, wow, wow, wow.
Rainbow!
What is that?
What did that do?
Okay, did we just go in here random bullshit?
Uh, swoop-de-loop, uh, wish me luck.
Oh, wait, it's not even mom.
It's blastocyst.
I thought it was the end.
Dealing good damage here.
Hell yeah.
There we go.
More range.
Random hearts.
Give it.
Angels are coming.
Seraphim.
Following familiar with the fire.
Upset!
Fucking fires!
No!
I don't know what to take.
Uh...
Let's...
Don't shoot me.
Following familiar with the fires.
Slow homing tears.
And some kind of big key.
And a contract.
Let's do this one.
Active contrition, tears up, and something forgiven.
Plus one.
Eternal heart.
Oh, is that the white one?
Okay, okay.
Allows angel rooms to appear even if a devil deal has been taken on the current run.
Deal chance reduction is decreased.
Oh, wait a minute.
So that means...
If I want angel rooms, I would have to...
not take devil deals.
That actually makes so much sense.
If you make a deal with the devil, you're not allowed entry into heaven.
Right?
Deal chance reduction is decreased.
Okay.
Active contrition.
I also have a usable card that I didn't use, so I don't know what it does.
See ya!
I don't like those fires.
Why are the fires evil there?
I don't get that.
Okay, this is the final stage.
You to row two.
Alright, alright.
Oh, not this shit.
They're gonna spawn a million things.
But it's okay, because I also have a million things.
Nice.
This way.
Oh, it's one of those things.
Oh, what the hell is this?
That is messed up.
Nice.
What's this?
A library?
Celebrity for dummies?
In homing tiers and increased range for the current room?
Monster manual.
Summon's a random familiar that lasts for the rest of the floor.
Hmm.
I mean, for the rest of the floor.
That's great.
I'll take it.
There's only one floor left.
Oh wait, I can take the other one too.
This is just for the room though.
Shwoop the voop is so good though.
In homing tiers.
Hmm.
I don't know.
Wait, there's another?
Oh wait, that's the one I just took.
Okay, okay.
Homing tiers and increased.
That's just for one room.
Maybe it's better for the boss actually.
Shwoop the voop is just the one time and then it's over, right?
But the laser or the homing tiers could be pretty good.
Also, what are these weird tentacles from the ground even doing with the tendrils?
What is their function?
Get frozen there.
What's happening?
What a terrible something.
I took damage and then things happened.
Let's heal up again.
We can't.
Uh oh.
This is scary.
We got a shwoop it I think.
That is beautiful.
I died.
No, not like this man.
Come on.
Bullshit.
Okay, one more.
One last horror.
We have a library right there.
And we don't have a map.
Is that the trade-off?
Come here.
What even are you?
Kind of evil child.
Evil spawn.
Where are you going?
Trying to juke me.
Not today.
The virus.
Poison's enemies on contact.
Poison touch.
But I don't want to touch enemies.
What's that?
The Bible.
Gain flight for the current room.
And you know what?
Why not?
No.
I'll take this.
Being able to fly.
Yeah!
Look at that.
Flymian.
What a horror...
I wish I could read that text!
Wait, what happened?
I became demon girl now.
I don't know what's going on.
What is happening?
I only have one HP as well.
Bro, what is this?
Wait, he's dead.
Oh, look at this!
We got a special rock here.
Let's get ready to destroy that.
We have a bomb now.
Boink!
We got two bombs back.
Not too shabby.
Right rage.
Yes, please.
Very good.
Good range!
No way.
Oh, the bird is out now.
But I'm almost dead.
Jesus Christ.
Nice.
Get that healing.
Fly me!
Oh, we also have a special rock here!
Nice.
Oh, that's evil.
Wait, I had a pill?
Bombs are key.
I don't know what that means.
Range down.
Man.
Too bad.
Boink!
That's for you.
Oh, but I don't have flying anymore, so this is going to be...
Nice.
We somehow did it.
Why am I suddenly so fast?
Like, I just gained a bunch of speed.
The last room I was in, it didn't have this much speed.
Wait, where am I supposed to go?
Oh.
I didn't even see that door.
I think we ate a pill that made us go to 1 HP, and I don't know how.
Or what pill that was.
It's time for Larry.
Okay, good.
Great start, actually.
Nipstick.
Oh, we get the range back.
We're flip-flopping on range right now.
Plus range, minus range, plus range, minus range.
Alright, let's go.
It's the timer.
A hundred demon now.
And extra damage.
Wait, wait.
We're not going to take devil deals.
We're avoiding that.
That's right.
You know what?
Let's try this.
Three.
Let's see what it does.
We have this.
Right, rage.
That's all there.
We gained a coin.
Okay.
There's also some kind of inscription up here.
You see that?
One, two, two, one, three.
Huh?
This looks like a D&D dice.
Or die.
You know, a twenty-sided one.
Uh-oh.
I'm going to blow it up, I guess.
I'll take no chances.
What am I doing?
I thought I couldn't traverse the fires for some reason.
Ah!
What a troll.
Man, having speed really does do a lot of good things for you.
That's for you!
Oh, I thought I could blow it up.
A pill?
Okay.
I don't mind that.
That's okay.
These flies are annoying, though.
Why am I so fast?
Wait, what is making me so fast?
Speed here?
Huh?
There's nothing that makes me fast.
There's only this one.
And, yeah, I don't get it.
Why am I fast?
Maybe it's like a modifier on the floor or something?
Ouch.
That's a eternal heart!
It shall not be eternal, though, not in my hands.
It's gonna last approximately one second.
Okay, maybe two seconds?
Not bad.
I don't even know what that is.
A bunch of crosses?
Scapular.
Pray for a miracle.
When damage down the last half heart, automatically gain one soul heart and activate only once per room.
Ooh.
Whoa, that seems really good.
Holy shit.
I love that.
Very nice.
Per room!
More pills?
Yeah!
Tears up.
I think I'm getting better at dodging projectiles.
But, maybe it also has something to do with the fact that I'm flying very fast.
Ah, but look at me!
I pray to the gods and I receive answers.
Oh, God.
Okay.
I don't have a key, though.
That means I can't go back and get it now.
Haha, man.
Fate is cruel.
Monstro, it's not too bad.
That was so clean.
We got a glass eye, more damage and luck!
We like that.
Ooh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hold on.
I'm not gonna go in there.
Because it will decrease my chances of getting angel room.
I am on the good side this time around.
I've got the Bible in hand.
There's no way I'm colluding with the devil.
We're going full angel.
Oh, yeah, we had eternal heart as well!
I forgot!
Huge!
Oh, let's do this one.
Ah, let's not.
I don't have any keys.
Oh, this is a tough room.
Yeah, there's no way I can not get hit against this shit.
Hardest enemies in the game.
I think these are actually the hardest enemies in the game.
So far.
I hate them with all my heart.
Wow, that was close.
I think my tiny size helped me out a little bit there.
Cheers.
Little jumping jacks.
Alright, come on.
They're so un... like... I hate this enemy design.
I really do.
It's just... Oh, I touched them.
Get poison nerd.
There you go.
Poison for you.
Just the fact that you have to wait for them to pop out is annoying.
Annoying enemy design.
Thank you.
Ah, oh, these guys are very tanky.
I think.
Uh-oh.
Okay, so...
Oh, wait a minute.
Oh!
I understand what's happening.
So, when I reach 1 HP...
The horror's coming out tits and all!
We're super fast.
And the fucking text on screen comes that I can never read.
I've still not read it fully to this day.
But yeah, that's what's happening.
Look at this.
Ah-ha!
Tactics.
Now we're gonna blow this up.
We also have the Bible in case we need it.
Good stuff.
Ah-ah.
Uh, smaller?
I think yes.
We like that.
But with 1 HP going in there?
Ah, you know what?
I think it's okay.
Let's do it.
Wish me luck.
No, it's not...
No, he's gonna shoot purple shit at me.
I'm gonna die.
Right?
That's the purple guy?
Or not?
Oh, it's not, okay.
What's he doing?
Keep doing that.
I like that.
Oh, here comes the purple stuff.
We got supper.
Oh, that's massive.
We love supper.
Man, that just reminds me.
I have made an amazing chorizo soup.
With potatoes and green kale.
And it's in the fridge and it's waiting for me after this.
No cooking.
It's already done.
Oh my god.
What a feeling.
Mysterious liquid.
Ah, this is the one.
Yeah, okay, this is good.
This is a good item.
We like that.
We take those.
They shoot horizontal.
Yep, yep, yep, yep, yep.
Look at my radioactive tears here.
You don't wanna touch these bad boys.
Lovely.
Ah, no keys.
Oh.
So I guess we leave.
Yeah.
My work here is done.
I could go in here, but I can choose not to do anything.
We're leaving.
Phew.
Halfway through the run.
He's also radioactive.
I wonder if I was healing him there.
But I don't think so.
I'm not hitting him.
Okay, there we go.
Question mark card.
Copies the effect of I6.
Ooh.
Oh.
I like.
I like even more.
Health uphill is crazy pill.
I take those pills all the time.
They taste good.
Man, am I just low on damage here?
What's happening?
I feel like I'm not dealing any damage.
Arcade, I'm rich.
Three arcade machines.
Hmm.
I'm gonna blow them up.
At least one of them.
Thanks.
Now we're gonna gamble.
Double gamble.
Wait, what?
Oh, it died from the creep, I think.
Oh, okay.
It broke.
I was gambling too hard.
Come on!
Okay, fuck you.
Thanks.
Got a key back.
Very nice.
There's a pill in here.
It's unidentified, I'm gonna get it.
It's
wrong.
Yeah.
Something is definitely wrong.
Wow.
Good.
I have to utilize my insane range.
Like, it's really good.
Ah, but look at me.
Black tooth.
Chance to fire a poison too that deals double Isaac's damage.
Only 3% though.
Increases with luck.
I mean, it's better than nothing.
Is it?
Chance to fire a tooth shot that...
Wait, what's the difference?
Black tooth and tooth shot?
I'm gonna take this one, I guess.
I honestly don't know what's best.
Wow, look at me dodging.
How am I making this happen?
Okay, I couldn't have made it happen.
Okay, that's fine.
Yo.
Oh, I really wanna buy this one.
I don't have enough money.
Let's go for 150 here.
A black candle has appeared!
Ooh.
Cool.
We did indeed reach a checkpoint there.
Aw, man.
I can't believe it.
Please die!
Thank you.
Oh wait, I can just stand here.
No, I can't.
The faster you are, the more you can angle your shots as well.
Nice.
Yeah, you know what?
Let's just go for it.
The ratchet.
I feel like there's three bosses that sound very different in name but are very similar in design.
I'm constantly confused by this.
Wow, the instant jump, man!
It's freaking impossible to dodge.
Unless you're already moving.
No, no, no, no.
Okay, we're good, we're good.
And yeah, we're at 1 HP now.
What the fuck?
Oh, we weren't done.
Placenza.
Good.
Wait, why is there no... I want angel rooms!
Alright, fine.
I'm not done here though.
We just... lost damage?
Something was occurring in that room only.
Wait, what?
Oh, right!
That heals.
That's pretty good.
There you go.
Lots of green goop for you.
Toxic.
You get close to me, you got sick.
No!
Die, die, die!
Whoa, Liberty Cap.
Chance to gain a random passive mushroom effect for the room.
Sounds good to me.
Friends till the end.
Friends till the end?
Uh, flies, I guess?
What's that?
Big chubby!
Chop, chop!
Happy to see me.
Oh, nice, we healed again.
I feel like that item is a little bit weird in design compared to the rest of the items in the game so far.
The fact that you just passively heal every half minute?
That's weird, isn't it?
Nice.
Run into my creep!
Now, this room...
Why not?
Uh, wait a second.
You know what?
Let's go crazy here.
I need to see what's going on here.
Alright!
Massive!
Not bad!
I'll take it!
This room is still closed.
I want to go up to the arcade again and get some healing.
We have no more healing.
Oh!
I went a little close to the sun there.
Okay, let's go.
Moving on!
Okay.
Uh, this doesn't look very good.
With extra speed, that becomes easier.
Oh, we gotta take out the white ones first.
I heal very nice!
Let's just sit here and snipe them at range.
Not bad!
I can't get there.
I could fly, but I'm not gonna.
Oh, shit.
That's evil.
What the hell, man?
Yeah, this room sucks.
Go!
Oh, I'm in danger.
Yeah, I'm in big danger!
Almost dead here.
What the fuck?!
He shot a laser!
Oh, much needed.
Much needed.
Good.
Very good.
Oh, I'm gonna get that money.
Uh, let's fly.
Oh, you want coins?
I've got coins, but I don't wanna be there!
No, thanks.
I'm gonna go in here.
Oh, that's a lot of more... that's a lot of damage.
Very good.
We like that.
That is actually such great news.
Teleport to the shop?
I didn't mean to do that!
Come on.
I don't know what the shop is.
I could teleport there.
Let's do it.
Oh, no, it's green!
I guess the shop is ripped now.
Steam sale?
Come on, man.
Fuck, the spiders.
Man.
Holy shit.
Fuck, I put it off!
I hate when they shoot lasers!
I've never seen that before this run.
Uh...
Kill these guys.
I'm gonna come back and grab that.
Actually, grab it and...
Ah, kill the boss first and then come back and grab it.
Oh, you're gonna do that stuff, okay.
I don't like this.
Okay, he stopped at least.
I met someone else who did that constantly, you know?
Your steed is gone!
What are you gonna do now?
Huge.
Banages.
I'm going back and grabbing the heart.
I think we're leaving.
Yeah, we're leaving.
So this is now the mom...
Cheers.
Oh!
Should I?
I have a lot of money.
I'm doing it.
Give up.
Okay, see ya.
Imagine if there was like an achievement for leaving the game after that message.
Don't leave the house today?
I never do.
Come on, give me some actual good stuff here.
You're throwing your life away?
I mean...
I don't like these messages.
They make me sad.
Come on!
Okay, give me an item!
You look fat, you should exercise.
That hit home.
You'll never be forgiven.
Stephen lives?
Who's Stephen?
Sunray's on your little face.
That's actually such a good feeling.
Am I gonna spend all my money?!
Go fuck yourself!
Unbelievable.
This way.
Whoa, he has a range.
Wow.
I'm hitting nothing.
Dude, I have no damage.
Okay.
Yeah, we're probably gonna get a key here.
Fuck me, why is that happening?!
Boo hoo, I hate it.
No, we couldn't use the key there.
Oh, that's a lot of enemies.
Come back here.
Bro, it feels like I'm doing no damage.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
There's another worm.
He's gone.
Here!
Yeah!
Let's fucking go.
Evil fire.
Sometimes you just have that feeling, and you know where it is.
You want bombs?
Here, have some.
Appreciate it.
Wow.
Dude, I have so much HP, what the hell?!
Bombs cursed, plus five poison bombs.
Bomb damage, poisons enemies, and bomb explosions leave behind poison gas.
Isaac is immune to poison effects.
Amazing!
Okay, well, that's good.
Wait.
That sounds pretty damn good.
What's that?
Teardrop charm.
There's a chance of lock-based shots to be fired.
Wait, wait, do I have some of that?
No, I don't.
Equivalent of plus four lock.
So it's actually kind of bad for me right now.
I have nothing that modifies my...
Well, no, I don't.
Bombs.
Wait, wait.
I need to go to that treasure room, dude.
We got to find a key.
There's got to be a key here.
Like, hello?
Let's look for suspicious rocks.
Don't see anything.
Let me...
Nah.
Down here.
Wow.
Coin.
Not exactly what a man needs.
You want health?
Okay.
That was a waste.
I'm going to try and destroy him in a second here.
Huh?
Oh, that was an enemy.
I see.
Come on, give me a key.
Just one key.
There we go.
We got the key.
Hold on, I want more.
Evil fire.
Don't hit me.
It tried to hit me.
It missed.
Wait, there's another room.
Oh, we got keys, but we also have these killer machines.
Ho, ho, ho, ho.
Outplayed, nerd.
Look at that.
Yike.
Hey, hey, hey.
Oh, wait, I almost...
I could go in there if I wanted.
No, no.
Let's save it.
No.
I'm going to blow this up.
Fuck these machines.
They wronged me.
Damage up.
Chance increases with luck.
Nah.
Nice.
Now we go...
Ow!
Not that way.
That was a mistake.
Kill him, kill him, kill him, kill him.
Good.
Wow.
Ah!
At least I'm getting all the keys I could ever dream of.
Let's go get this treasure.
What is it going to be?
A shopping bag?
A dead tooth.
What is it with all these teeth?
Firing creates an aura around Isaac that poisons...
Oh, even more poison.
All right.
Not bad.
Ah!
I healed.
Very nice.
Exchanges quantities of bombs and keys.
Ooh!
That is exciting, but I do have the poison on the thing, so I don't think I want to.
It's a random card.
It's an active.
I don't like that.
Let's re-roll here.
Oh, look at that!
We got an aura.
I see now.
Oh, it's random how many coins it needs.
I see.
Battery pack.
Blue heart.
We don't know what this is, but it's a big battery.
We know what it is.
Now, that's exciting.
A sharp plug.
Infinite charge at a cost.
Uh-oh.
Using an uncharged item will exchange half red heart for each missing charge segment.
Uses red hearts first.
Stops working when Isaac is at half heart.
Wait, wait, wait.
Using a punch.
Oh, uncharged item.
I see.
I mean, it could be good, I guess.
In my case here.
We can do a lot of flying.
Uh, this one was... nah.
Time for the boss.
Wish me luck.
It's mob time!
With a little heart on it, too.
Get poisoned.
Wow, you just came back immediately there.
Oh, god.
Oh, no.
I'm falling apart.
Eh, it's not good.
Wait, where am I?
Oh, I see.
Couldn't find my character.
Eh, I think we're gonna... maybe die here.
It's gonna be close.
Uh, we are... okay.
We somehow made it.
Man, that was not good.
Mom's underwear.
Oh, angel!
Oh, this one is good.
I like that.
Fantastic.
The shield is good.
Oh, that is one toxic shield.
Look at that.
Wait, what?
Are you challenging me?
Okay.
I have the power of god on my side.
Peace.
Not too bad.
Whoa!
All right.
Balls of steel.
Oh, it gives me hearts!
Two blue hearts.
Two balls.
Made of steel.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So far, so good.
Hell yeah.
Oh, this is gonna be tough.
This is a crazy room.
Wait, they all died?
Why?
Oh, man, my shield is so good!
Love this shield.
Lazy worm.
More damage, less shot speed.
Yeah.
Oh, it replaces.
I thought it was just an item, in that case.
And no.
Oh, he's released.
The madman has escaped.
Here.
Oh, no.
Ho, ho.
Try it.
Oh, you assholes.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Not too shabby, eh?
My shield, you can't win.
Okay, I guess you can...
Ah!
I shouldn't have spoke so soon!
Dude, I do no damage!
Horrible.
Oh, what?
Gamer!
Holy crap!
If that wasn't gamer, then I don't know what is gamer.
That was incredibly gamer.
Can't tell me that wasn't...
Nice!
And we get healing, that's huge.
In fact, I would love to get a lot of healing.
Come on, give me hearts.
Come on, man!
Alright, fuck you then.
Uh, you're just gonna go in a circle there, that's cool.
Oh man, why you gotta be down there, huh?
Where you at?
Good stuff?
Man, I need healing.
Give me a good amount of hearts.
He's sitting in my poop!
What, what?
Oh, it was the little eye that hit me, I think.
Wow, wow, wow, wow.
He did.
Here.
How good am I?
Okay, but it didn't really do anything.
Oh, another secret!
Unbelievable.
Well, is it really a secret?
Was that panic button?
Just before taking damage, if charged, automatically use I6 active item?
If charged?
Huh?
Oh, I see.
That's not, I mean, unless I get a better active, it's not really gonna help me.
I hate these rooms so much.
Yeah.
Alright, that's fine.
Wait, what was this one?
Damage, but less shot speed.
Wait, eight points.
Nah, this is definitely better.
Man, I hate this thing in front of me.
Get away from me.
This shield is so good against these guys.
How am I taking damage?
What was that?
Fucking hell.
Oh, no!
Come on.
Okay, okay, thank God.
Oh, massive, massive.
Uh, we could go in there now.
Is that wise, though?
I think I need some more healing.
There's a bunch of rooms we didn't do yet.
No, come on.
Wait, what is this one doing again?
Random passive mushroom effect for the room?
I don't even know what that means.
What is a passive random mushroom effect?
No, I don't like this one.
It feels too slow.
Oh, wait, wrong way.
Coins.
Except I can't get to you.
Oh, no, this room is gonna kill me.
These guys are so tough.
My shield does not work against lasers.
Trust me, I've tried.
All right, all right, that works.
We got him.
Oh, my God.
What the fuck?!
Oh, there's a button!
I see... Oh, it's over.
No, I'm gonna die here.
There's no way I survived this shit.
It's over.
How?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no.
Huge.
Yes.
Look, no!
It spiked!
But, hold on, I can fly.
I can fly.
We're flying.
I'm making absolutely sure that I'm not gonna...
Okay!
Nice.
Oh, man, oh, man.
Okay, we still have rooms.
Go for the rooms.
Wait, there's a heart in here.
Oh, shit!
Didn't even see that.
Huge.
All right, all right, we got flies.
That's okay.
Nice.
That's not gonna help me.
Pride.
A book?
What is that?
Anarchist cookbook.
Someone six randomly plays troll.
I feel like there's another item that does the exact same.
Bookworm.
Wait, oh, we have three out of three on that.
So, what does that do?
Oh, that we shoot randomly two at a time, or what?
Is that the change?
Or is it the one I just had?
Let me see here.
No, this is the randomly summoned troll bombs.
Well, that's pretty cool, shooting two of these.
Whoa, now we should go get that item that increases our luck with shot-based thingies.
Except I think that was the last floor.
Maybe.
I could be wrong.
We gotta check.
Brother, brother, brother, brother, come on, come on, what's that?
Emergency contact.
Oh, yeah, I like that.
Okay.
Go!
Huh?
Oh, there's spikes on it!
I didn't even see that!
Oh, crap.
Good thing we can fly!
I'll take it.
I'll take that.
What's this?
Die shard!
We roll all items and pickups in the room?
No.
I need that, but I will take it.
Oh, it's a usable!
Oh, that's interesting.
Okay, okay.
That's gonna be exciting.
You guys are chained up, huh?
Too bad.
Over here.
Can I destroy this?
Got a big room here.
What's with these tentacles?
I guess if you come too close, they kind of look like spine crawlers, actually.
From Starcraft.
Uh, should we go into that room down there?
I think it's a bad idea.
Also, I don't... Oh, no, I can't get the other one back!
Uh-oh.
But, here's what I can do.
Here's what I can do.
We're gonna go into a room like this one.
Reroll!
My little unicorn!
Temporary badass!
Gain invincibility and bonus speed!
Disables tears?
Oh...
Okay, grants contact damage.
Mmm, is it better than the Bible, though?
Nah.
The Bible is the one true.
Book.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Or at least fight the boss.
No, stop picking that up.
Or maybe I will pick it up now.
Since more damage with this?
Yeah, I think it's maybe better now.
Okay.
Oh, I thought it was mom time!
I keep fucking thinking that.
Blast assist and shit.
Wow.
Man, the shot speeds are really low for some reason.
Why is that?
Like, what?
What is happening?
Ew.
Is that poop in a bowl?
It lunch?
Is that what I had for lunch?
Oh.
Mom!
Are you serving this for me?
Wait, this was a fake boss room.
Wait, what?
Okay.
Whoa, I'm so confused.
All right, all right, we got an eye.
We killed it.
Good.
Now we focus on mom.
I'm flying.
Oh, Halo has appeared.
Wait, what?
What just happened?
Did we just banish mom with the Bible?
Is that what just happened?
Bookworm three out of three.
I think we... Wait.
What if I go back now?
Instead of opening this chest?
Wait a minute.
What if I leave?
I got to open it, though.
I got to do it.
Look at us crying so much.
Like, you would think we would have been dried out by now.
Let's see the butt.
It's butt time.
Oh, what a butt.
What did we find in there?
What was that?
Mom's cooking.
I guess.
I... Peacack?
Crow baby.
That was a good session, guys.
Two wins, I think?
Or three?
Two wins.
I think two wins.
I learned a lot, by the way.
I feel like this was the knowledge stream.
Crazy good stuff.
This game is so good, I almost forgot.
Well, you didn't play it for a couple of years?
I guess Isaac is bad.
And then you see it again.
Oh, yeah, right.
This game rocks.
Noah's Hazel today, except we kind of became a Hazel.
Can you really call it Noah's Hazel?
The game just wanted me to become a Hazel.
I'm getting better at this game, thank you very much.
I think so.
I think this game has a lot of knowledge gates.
Where if you have the knowledge, you can suddenly turn things around.
For example, bombing the rocks to make a bridge.
That could get you the heart you need to survive the boss, you know?
Like, that is an insane advantage to have, for example.
Oliver, enable the gym mod in the menu.
Oh, wait.
So I did have to do something in the menu.
Wait, mods.
Press tap to enable.
Enable?
The gym button has been enabled.
Next time we're going to have gym.
How good is that?
I was so sad to see it not working today.
Man, oh man.
Dude, I am so exhausted.
This game is really exhausting, though.
Because you don't have a single moment of break, you know?
It's like you're in a flow state for four hours.
Five hours?
What the fuck?
We've been playing for five hours?
I thought we were at four.
I thought I went over three hours, and I was like, okay, we're at four now, but yeah.
Oh my god.
Maybe read the Bible next stream for immersion?
I don't know if I want to do that.
It's kind of boring.
I don't like the Bible.
It's a boring book.
I've read much better books.
The text you were trying to read, what a horrible night to have a curse.
That's what it says.
Okay.
It's a reference to Castlevania 2.
I see.
I've never played Castlevania, so I wouldn't know.
But, like, nobody can read that fast enough.
It is literally on screen for half a second.
Right ear, Oliver Ice Extreme, left ear Bible in Chinese.
I love that, Kaylee.
I feel like I should upload that on my channel.
Should I do that?
Wouldn't that be hilarious?
And then have one of those really cringe thumbnails of, like, some guy being enlightened by it or something?
Oh no.
That is funny.
Oh yeah, you have to hold control for quite a long time to drop trinkets.
Ah, okay, okay, thanks.
Yeah.
So it was control.
I was remembering that right, but yeah.
I guess I forgot I had to hold it.
Thanks.
You should read the Chinese Bible for the voiceover.
I can't speak Chinese, though.
It will be a horrible pronunciation.
It's not gonna be good, guys.
You're gonna hate it.
Also, what day is it today?
Let's see here.
Okay, there's still two days.
We can maybe make it happen.
I mean, I could have, like, some kind of translation tool live that translates my voice to Chinese while I...
Chinese, right, English, left.
That's horrible.
Hire a translator.
How about I hire someone to do sign language instead?
We're gonna have a little sign language guy in the bottom right.
I go, fuck!
I need more poop!
And the guy's, like, doing the poop sign aggressively in the bottom right of the stream.
That would actually be amazing.
Man, I wish I had so much money that I could just, you know, do that.
That I could just go on Fiverr or whatever those websites are and hire someone like that.
I need you to come to my house today.
You need to be on video, on a live stream.
You're gonna just translate what I'm saying.
And here's a camera.
And I'll see you in four hours.
That would be hilarious.
You leveled up this stream playing very well.
I think so as well.
I definitely made some stupid mistakes, but overall, I think I'm getting more consistent progress in these runs.
Even the runs I didn't win, I got pretty far with it.
Next time, greed.
I'm gonna try greed next time.
I actually totally forgot about it this time.
I was in the zone, you know?
When you lose a run, I just click space and it goes right into it.
It's hard not to do, you know?
You just want to keep going.
Oh yeah, the Parlor Room compilation.
I haven't watched it, but I'm sure it's good.
Share it in the, what's it, in the Clips and Highlights channel if you want.
Feel free to do that.
Azazel tempted you too much.
Yeah, for sure.
Azazel is... Honestly though, after I've tried the infinite laser, man, Azazel is not even that good anymore after that.
The infinite laser, that's where it's at.
Binding of Isaac compilation is just a full stream.
Nah.
I think there's a lot of dead air.
Not dead air, but boring segments in the Isaac runs.
But then again, I don't know.
I don't know what it's like to watch Isaac gameplay.
I guess it's much more fun if you've played the game.
Because you know what all of this means and what that means.
And if you're watching someone who doesn't know anything about it, it's a lot more like, Oh, is he gonna realize X or... Oh, I can't wait to see Y happen because he's in, you know, a set situation.
Stuff like that.
But if you don't know the game and you're watching me, I'd have no idea what that would be like.
You're probably gonna be just as confused as I am most of the time.
Oh, Avetus, we should definitely have a maybe towards the end of this game where I watched some of the first gameplay for sure, just like we did with Minecraft.
I think that could be fun because with games where knowledge is a big deal, it's always kind of fun to see where you started right when you didn't know anything.
Right?
Wouldn't that be fun?
See how bad I was at the beginning.
I say that now and before I never get better and this is my peak.
I have plateaued.
Nah, I'm sure I'll get better.
I got a little tilted at some point today.
I forgot when.
There was something about... Was it the chests?
I didn't have the keys for it, but I got a little tilted from that.
But then when a new run starts, you're just getting back into it immediately, you know?
Okay, guys, I have been thinking about this chorizo soup so much ever since we found supper in the game.
I'm going to go now.
Thank you for watching.
It is such a blast playing this game.
Thanks for being here.
Thanks for all the subs.
I appreciate it.
You guys are the best.
You're making this actually happen for me, you know?
The fact that I can do this full time.
Just sitting here playing Isaac and getting addicted.
You guys are funding my crack addiction, you know that, right?
Just making you guys aware of it.
Have a good one.